<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Cash Weaver</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/</link><description>Recent content on Cash Weaver</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cashweaver.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>At Least Two of the Same</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/2021-12-02-12-00-at_least_two_of_the_same/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/2021-12-02-12-00-at_least_two_of_the_same/</guid><description>I always do at least 2 of the same, so I can see where my work was intentional and where it was accidental.
For example When I do sets I make 2-4-6 of the same shape/size/color. They started out being cousins, then became sisters, now they are twins. Knowing I can form a shape with intention was important to me. It strengthened my skill.
BUT there is a place for &amp;lsquo;form-finding&amp;rsquo; which I think describes how you made these shapes you are showing us.</description></item><item><title>Polyphasic Sleep: 40 Day Trial Results</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/2021-12-02-12-15-polyphasic_sleep_40_day_trial_results/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/2021-12-02-12-15-polyphasic_sleep_40_day_trial_results/</guid><description>What would you do with another few hours every day? This was the thought that pulled me into attempting a polyphasic sleep schedule.
Note that I didn&amp;rsquo;t keep good notes while I was researching the intricacies of polyphasic sleep. There will be quite a few uncited claims.
Why Change My Sleep Schedule? In short: to live longer.
I expect to live for another 50.4 years1. I was getting an average of nine hours of sleep every night prior to stating this experiment.</description></item><item><title>The First Lesson</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/2021-12-02-12-44-the_first_lesson/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/2021-12-02-12-44-the_first_lesson/</guid><description> Muad&amp;rsquo;Dib learned rapidly because his first training was in how to learn. And the first lesson of all was the basic trust that he could learn. It&amp;rsquo;s shocking to find how many people do not believe they can learn, and how many more believe learning to be difficult. Muad&amp;rsquo;Dib knew that every experience carries its lesson.
Princess Irulan, Dune</description></item><item><title>The First Lesson</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the-first-lesson/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the-first-lesson/</guid><description> Muad&amp;rsquo;Dib learned rapidly because his first training was in how to learn. And the first lesson of all was the basic trust that he could learn. It&amp;rsquo;s shocking to find how many people do not believe they can learn, and how many more believe learning to be difficult. Muad&amp;rsquo;Dib knew that every experience carries its lesson.
Princess Irulan, Dune</description></item><item><title>Links</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/links/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/links/</guid><description>Links 2021 May Theory of Change by Aaron Swartz
A theory of change is the opposite of a theory of action &amp;mdash; it works backwards from the goal, in concrete steps, to figure out what you can do to achieve it. To develop a theory of change, you need to start at the end and repeatedly ask yourself, &amp;quot;Concretely, how does one achieve that?&amp;quot;
Cached Selves by Anna Salamon</description></item><item><title>Gmail in Emacs with mbsync and mu4e</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read-email-in-emacs-with-mbsync-isync-and-mu4e/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read-email-in-emacs-with-mbsync-isync-and-mu4e/</guid><description>This is a guide to setting up access to email from a Gmail account (eg: @gmail.com) within doom emacs using mu, mbsync (isync), and mu4e (mu for emacs).
You may have to complete additional steps if you are not using doom emacs, Gmail, or if your set-up differs from mine in other ways.
Prerequisites Please be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve completed these steps before continuing:
Required Software Install mbsync version &amp;gt;= 1.</description></item><item><title>Gmail in Emacs with notmuch and lieer</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read-email-from-gmail-with-notmuch-and-lieer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read-email-from-gmail-with-notmuch-and-lieer/</guid><description>This is a guide to setting up access to email (eg: @gmail.com) within doom emacs using notmuch and lieer.
You may have to complete additional steps if you are not using doom emacs or if your set-up differs from mine in other ways.
Prerequisites Please be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve completed these steps before continuing:
Required Software lieer
git clone https://github.com/gauteh/lieer.git cd lieer pip3 install -r requirements.txt notmuch</description></item><item><title>Create an OAuth2 Client ID</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/create-an-oauth2-client-id/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/create-an-oauth2-client-id/</guid><description>A short guide to creating an OAuth2 Client ID through the Google Cloud Console.
Create a new OAuth2 Client ID These steps are based on the steps outlined by ccrusius.
Navigate to the Cloud Console. Choose an existing project or create a new one. Select &amp;ldquo;APIs &amp;amp; Services&amp;rdquo; from the navigation menu. Select &amp;ldquo;Credentials&amp;rdquo;. Create new credentials of type &amp;ldquo;OAuth Client ID&amp;rdquo;. Choose application type &amp;ldquo;Other&amp;rdquo;. Choose a name for the client.</description></item><item><title>Tracking Time with Tasker and Google Calendar</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tracking-time-with-tasker-and-google-calendar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tracking-time-with-tasker-and-google-calendar/</guid><description>In the spirit of personal time tracking, I thought I would share my method as well. I&amp;rsquo;ll write a follow-up, or amend this post, with the relevant source code at some point.
I started tracking my time a few months ago so I could have data to back up questions about how much I time I was giving to studying, working, cooking, chores, friends, etc. The solutions I found for tracking personal time didn&amp;rsquo;t mesh with the way I wanted to track time:</description></item><item><title>Goals for 2021</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/goals-for-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/goals-for-2021/</guid><description>The unexamined life is not worth living, man.
These are vague goals, in no particular order, for myself in 2021. I think it would be helpful to break them down into shorter-term and specific goals. That&amp;rsquo;ll come later. For now&amp;hellip;
Give more time to the people in my life. Keep in touch with friends. Learn my working limit and respect it. Become more comfortable sitting quietly in a room alone.</description></item><item><title>Custom Anki Notes</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/custom-anki-notes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/custom-anki-notes/</guid><description>I use Anki to help myself remember the things I learn. Anki is flashcard software that integrates spaced repetition and active recall testing. I found creating cards, as well as managing existing cards, was easier after creating custom note types to represent specific information.
Most of my cards include a common field: Source. I like to keep track of where I found the information that went into the card, be that Wikipedia or a textbook or otherwise.</description></item></channel></rss>