<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Cash Weaver</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/</link><description>Recent content on Cash Weaver</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 17:46:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cashweaver.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Write Usefully</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/how_to_write_usefully/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 17:46:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/how_to_write_usefully/</guid><description>Summary A useful essay is one which is novel, correct, important, and strong:
A novel essay communicates a &amp;ldquo;new thing&amp;rdquo; (point of view, fact, opinion, etc) to at least some of its audience. A correct essay is factually accurate; insofar as is possible. An important essay matters to at least some people. You can measure it by the product of the number of people for which your points matter and how much it matters to those people.</description></item><item><title>The Myth of the Myth of the 10x Programmer</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the_myth_of_the_myth_of_the_10x_programmer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 17:30:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the_myth_of_the_myth_of_the_10x_programmer/</guid><description>Notes I don’t know anyone 10x faster than their peers in solving well-defined programming problems.
&amp;hellip;
[H]ighly productive developers (10x or otherwise) are problem-solving at a much higher level. Their productivity won’t be apparent from a narrow test, any more than the overall skill of a world-class football player would be apparent from (say) how fast they could run the 100m dash.
The most productive developers are solving big problems, and are bringing judgment and experience to bear on essential design, architecture, and “build vs use existing library” decisions.</description></item><item><title>Bloom's Taxomomy: Cognitive Domain</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/bloom_s_taxomomy_cognitive_domain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:24:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/bloom_s_taxomomy_cognitive_domain/</guid><description>&amp;hellip; [A hierarchical model] used to classify educational learning objectives into levels of complexity and specificity. &amp;hellip; The cognitive domain list has been the primary focus of most traditional education and is frequently used to structure curriculum learning objectives, assessments and activities.
In order from least complex to most complex:
Knowledge Comprehension Application Analysis Synthesis Evaluation Anderson proposed proposed a revision of Bloom&amp;rsquo;s cognitive taxomomy (in order from least complex to most complex):</description></item><item><title>Permastore</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/permastore/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:05:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/permastore/</guid><description>Extremely long-term or lasting memory which forms following extensive training, learning, or experience.
Bahrick posited the concept in https://books.google.com/books?vid=ISBN10.1037/0096-3445.113.1.1.</description></item><item><title>Relational Processing</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/relational_processing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 11:44:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/relational_processing/</guid><description>A technique of studying/learning where one emphasizes the relationships between pieces of information.
&amp;hellip; [R]elational processing refers to the encoding of similarities and differences across pieces of information. For example, sorting words into categories, ordering sentences to create a coherent text, and explaining why each subsequent step in a science experiment follows the preceding step all involve comparing to-be-remembered events to each other.
Memory in Educational Settings</description></item><item><title>Item-specific Processing</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/item_specific_processing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 11:40:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/item_specific_processing/</guid><description>A technique of studying/learning where one emphasizes features of the pieces of information.
Item-specific processing involves encoding the various characteristics or properties of a particular piece of information. For example, judging the pleasantness of a word, filling in missing letters in a text, and creating a mental image of each step in a science experiment all focus the learner on a single to-be-remembered item.
Memory in Educational Settings</description></item><item><title>Testing Effect</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/testing_effect/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 11:36:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/testing_effect/</guid><description>Retrieving a piece of information from memory will increase ones ability to recall that piece of information over long periods of time. A common example would be using tests as a tool for study. The student has to attempt to recall the information from memory while taking the test and thereby improves their recall.</description></item><item><title>Memory in Educational Settings</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/memory_in_educational_settings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 10:31:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/memory_in_educational_settings/</guid><description>Summary Retrieval or re-experiencing a memory will increase retention. Studying should be somewhat difficult; neither too difficult that the subject is unable to overcome the challenge, nor too easy. The difficulty is a desirable feature of the process of studying in that the difficulty improves retention. One does not need to be aware of the specific benefits of a study method to benefit from them. The way you learned a piece of information as well as the cues/environment during retrieval control your ability to remember and utilize information.</description></item><item><title>Spaced Repetition</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/spaced_repetition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 15:26:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/spaced_repetition/</guid><description> Spaced repetition is an evidence-based learning technique that is usually performed with flashcards. Newly introduced and more difficult flashcards are shown more frequently, while older and less difficult flashcards are shown less frequently in order to exploit the psychological spacing effect. The use of spaced repetition has been proven to increase rate of learning.</description></item><item><title>Spacing Effect</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/spacing_effect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 15:26:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/spacing_effect/</guid><description> The spacing effect demonstrates that learning is more effective when study sessions are spaced out.</description></item><item><title>Desirable Difficulty</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/desirable_difficulty/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 15:13:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/desirable_difficulty/</guid><description>A desirable difficulty is a learning task that requires a considerable but desirable amount of effort, thereby improving long-term performance.
Examples include:
Retrieval practice (eg: flashcards) Spacing and interleaving (eg: Spaced Repetition) To determine whether a difficulty is desirable, use the following three guidelines:
The processing at encoding should be the same as the processing at retrieval. The processing at encoding should be the same as the processing during practice.</description></item><item><title>Ask HN: How do you learn complex, dense technical information?</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ask_hn_how_do_you_learn_complex_dense_technical_information/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 12:41:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ask_hn_how_do_you_learn_complex_dense_technical_information/</guid><description>Notes Essentially I think learning is fundamentally Pain. You have to take on the pain before the learning can alleviate it, if you try to skip the pain then you have only a superficial idea of what you&amp;rsquo;re talking about.
crdrost
Interestingly there is a concept in learning research called &amp;ldquo;desirable difficulty&amp;rdquo;. The idea is that learning something, forgetting it and then struggling to learn it again leads to faster learning times.</description></item><item><title>Tricks to start working despite not feeling like it</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tricks_to_start_working_despite_not_feeling_like_it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 04:11:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tricks_to_start_working_despite_not_feeling_like_it/</guid><description>Summary &amp;ldquo;Screw it, let&amp;rsquo;s do it&amp;rdquo; Start sloppy Start small</description></item><item><title>DND Notes</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/dnd_notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 19:23:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/dnd_notes/</guid><description>Eli Huhoi In Virradain&amp;rsquo;s flashback I&amp;rsquo;m Suko</description></item><item><title>How to Read a Paper</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/how_to_read_a_paper_2016_pdf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 12:19:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/how_to_read_a_paper_2016_pdf/</guid><description>How to Read a Paper The Three-Pass Approach The key idea is that you should read the paper in up to three passes, instead of starting at the beginning and plowing your way to the end. Each pass accomplishes specific goals and builds upon the previous pass: The first pass gives you a general idea about the paper. The second pass lets you grasp the paper&amp;rsquo;s content, but not its details.</description></item><item><title>Key practices for achieving large professional goals</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/key_practices_for_achieving_large_professional_goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 23:54:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/key_practices_for_achieving_large_professional_goals/</guid><description>Summary I attribute much of my success in 2019 to the practices of:
writing to develop my thoughts learning to focus I wrote a lot in 2019 &amp;hellip; This practice of writing resulted in a couple major changes:
I now use writing as a primary mechanism to develop my thoughts on a subject Writing is now a healthy habit for my professional skills and business Kuenzli mentions that they &amp;ldquo;really learned how to focus and extract much more value out of the time I have available&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>The Basic Problem of Democracy (1919)</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the_basic_problem_of_democracy_1919/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 23:10:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the_basic_problem_of_democracy_1919/</guid><description>Summary A well written essay whose thesis, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit embarrassed to say, eludes me.
Notes If we substitute the word indifference for the word liberty, we shall come much closer to the real intention that lies behind the classic argument. Liberty is to be permitted where differences are of no great moment. It is this definition which has generally guided practice. In times when men feel themselves secure, heresy is cultivated as the spice of life.</description></item><item><title>Monica, open source personal CRM</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/monica_open_source_personal_crm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 22:51:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/monica_open_source_personal_crm/</guid><description>I have a hard time keeping track of personal relationships. Perhaps this would be a helpful tool.</description></item><item><title>Habits Always Form</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/habits_always_form/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 22:40:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/habits_always_form/</guid><description>Summary Habits are always forming. No matter what you do, you’re also forming habits too. Keep that in mind with whatever you do.
When we talk about habits, we generally talk about learning good habits. Or forming good habits. Both of these outcomes suggest we can end up with the habits we want. And technically we can! But most of the habits we have are habits we ended up with after years of unconscious behavior.</description></item><item><title>Write thin to write fast</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/write_thin_to_write_fast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 21:52:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/write_thin_to_write_fast/</guid><description>Summary Set your editor&amp;rsquo;s column width very low &amp;hellip; 36 characters for me, [your mileage may vary].
Thinner columns help you read faster. Writing speed is dominated by reading speed. If you read faster, you write faster.
Thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve seem content width discussed often when it comes to reading. A width of 72 characters comes to mind, though I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where I picked that up. I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen content width discussed as often when it comes to writing.</description></item><item><title>README</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 20:32:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/readme/</guid><description>The purpose of this README is to explain some of the details in this collection of content. In no particular order:
I haven&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;written&amp;rdquo; all of the posts. I employ liberal use of quoting as a way of archiving. I use tags prefixed with @ to identify original authors (eg: @cashweaver). When PostA links to PostB, then a backlink to PostA will appear at the bottom of PostB (example). I often omit the source of a quote if there is only once source used in the entire post.</description></item><item><title>How I Write My Blog</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/how_i_write_my_blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 20:21:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/how_i_write_my_blog/</guid><description> I write and publish using Emacs, specifically Doom Emacs (my config), and a combination of org-roam and ox-hugo. I host the blog on github and store the post content in a separate github repo.</description></item><item><title>Read Gmail in Emacs with mbsync and mu4e</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read_gmail_in_emacs_with_mbsync_and_mu4e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 20:01:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read_gmail_in_emacs_with_mbsync_and_mu4e/</guid><description>This is a guide to setting up access to email from a Gmail account (eg: @gmail.com) within doom emacs using mu, mbsync (isync), and mu4e (mu for emacs).
You may have to complete additional steps if you are not using doom emacs, Gmail, or if your set-up differs from mine in other ways.
Prerequisites Please be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve completed these steps before continuing:
Required Software Install mbsync version &amp;gt;= 1.</description></item><item><title>Read Gmail in Emacs with notmuch and lieer</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read_gmail_in_emacs_with_notmuch_and_lieer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 19:56:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read_gmail_in_emacs_with_notmuch_and_lieer/</guid><description>This is a guide to setting up access to email (eg: @gmail.com) within doom emacs using notmuch and lieer.
You may have to complete additional steps if you are not using doom emacs or if your set-up differs from mine in other ways.
Prerequisites Please be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve completed these steps before continuing:
Required Software lieer
git clone https://github.com/gauteh/lieer.git cd lieer pip3 install -r requirements.txt notmuch</description></item><item><title>Create an OAuth2 Client ID</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/create_an_oauth2_client_id/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 19:48:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/create_an_oauth2_client_id/</guid><description>A short guide to creating an OAuth2 Client ID through the Google Cloud Console.
Create a new OAuth2 Client ID These steps are based on the steps outlined by ccrusius.
Navigate to the Cloud Console. Choose an existing project or create a new one. Select &amp;ldquo;APIs &amp;amp; Services&amp;rdquo; from the navigation menu. Select &amp;ldquo;Credentials&amp;rdquo;. Create new credentials of type &amp;ldquo;OAuth Client ID&amp;rdquo;. Choose application type &amp;ldquo;Other&amp;rdquo;. Choose a name for the client.</description></item><item><title>Three Components of Emotion</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/three_components_of_emotion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 01:03:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/three_components_of_emotion/</guid><description> A subjective experience. A physiological response. A behavioral, or expressive, response.</description></item><item><title>A Potter's Workbook</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/a_potter_s_workbook/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 11:27:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/a_potter_s_workbook/</guid><description>A Potter&amp;rsquo;s Workbook Skeleton Contents Acknowledgments Truth to Process As an apprentice at the Leach Pottery in 1964 and 1965, I helped produce a line of standard ware shapes. I remember vividly the moment when I realized that I was not learning shapes but processes, and that the way a thing is made and its appearance are one and the same.
Wondrous The Space Within The assignment is to make a cylinder, somewhat taller than it is wide, that suggests the greatest possible internal empty space for the given amount of clay.</description></item><item><title>Tsuyoku Naritai (I Want to Become Stronger)</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tsuyoku_naritai_i_want_to_become_stronger/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 12:43:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tsuyoku_naritai_i_want_to_become_stronger/</guid><description>The most important thing is that there should be progress. So long as you keep moving forward you will reach your destination; but if you stop moving you will never reach it.
Tsuyoku naritai is Japanese. Tsuyoku is “strong”; naru is “becoming,” and the form naritai is “want to become.” Together it means, “I want to become stronger,” and it expresses a sentiment embodied more intensely in Japanese works than in any Western literature I’ve read.</description></item><item><title>Noticing the Taste of Lotus</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/noticing_the_taste_of_lotus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 12:30:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/noticing_the_taste_of_lotus/</guid><description>Duncan Sabien sometimes talks about “lotus-eating”. He’s referring to a part of the Odyssey where they land on an island of “lotus-eaters”. It turns out that once you eat some of this kind of lotus, all you want to do is eat more. You stop caring about your other goals. The lotus just grabs your wants directly.
The idea of noticing the taste of lotus is closely related to mindfulness and attention.</description></item><item><title>Theory of Change</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/theory_of_change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 12:28:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/theory_of_change/</guid><description>I am increasingly convinced that the difference between effective and ineffective people is their skill at developing a theory of change.
A theory of change is the opposite of a theory of action — it works backwards from the goal, in concrete steps, to figure out what you can do to achieve it. To develop a theory of change, you need to start at the end and repeatedly ask yourself, “Concretely, how does one achieve that?</description></item><item><title>Exceed Your Level</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/exceed_your_level/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 12:25:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/exceed_your_level/</guid><description> There are no limits. There are plateaus, but you must not stay there, you must go beyond them. If it kills you, it kills you. A man must constantly exceed his level.
Bruce Lee</description></item><item><title>Deregulating Distraction, Moving Towards the Goal, and Level Hopping</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/deregulating_distraction_moving_towards_the_goal_and_level_hopping/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 12:24:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/deregulating_distraction_moving_towards_the_goal_and_level_hopping/</guid><description>I started doing NaNoWriMo in 2011, and I noticed something interesting: a vast majority of winners barely made it to 50,000 words. The goal of NaNoWriMo is to write 50k words in a month, so I wasn’t particularly surprised. However, from my interactions with others I found that a vast majority of these winners felt like they were pushing themselves to the limit, even though many of them were probably psychologically anchored below their actual limits.</description></item><item><title>There's No Speed Limit</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/there_s_no_speed_limit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 12:20:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/there_s_no_speed_limit/</guid><description> Kimo&amp;rsquo;s high expectations set a new pace for me. He taught me that &amp;ldquo;the standard pace is for chumps&amp;rdquo; — that the system is designed so anyone can keep up. If you&amp;rsquo;re more driven than most people, you can do way more than anyone expects. And this principle applies to all of life, not just school.</description></item><item><title>Attention Capital Theory</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/attention_capital_theory/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 12:17:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/attention_capital_theory/</guid><description>In modern knowledge work, the primary capital resource is human brains; or, more specifically, these brains’ ability to create new value through sustained attention. At the moment, most individuals and organizations are terrible at optimizing this resource, prioritizing instead the convenience and flexibility of persistent, unstructured messaging (e.g., email and IM). I predict that as this sector evolves, we’ll get better at optimizing attention capital, and accordingly leave behind our current culture of communication overload.</description></item><item><title>Deep Work Hypothesis</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/deep_work_hypothesis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 12:14:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/deep_work_hypothesis/</guid><description> The ability to [engage in Deep Work] is becoming more rare at the same time that it’s becoming more valuable in the knowledge sector. As a result, those individuals and organizations who put in the hard work to cultivate this skill will thrive.</description></item><item><title>Deep Work</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/deep_work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 12:12:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/deep_work/</guid><description>The ability to concentrate, without distraction, on a demanding task.</description></item><item><title>Meaningful Rest</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/meaningful_rest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:52:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/meaningful_rest/</guid><description>An exercise: Set a 5 minute timer, and list the things you want to do when you feel tired and low-energy. Then, set another 5 minute timer, and list the things you feel rejuvenated after having done - the things you like doing when low-energy.
If you’re anything like me, these lists are basically disjoint!
Most situations in my life have a default response, and that takes no effort to follow.</description></item><item><title>Monthly Newsletter as a Thinking Tool</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/monthly_newsletter_as_a_thinking_tool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:48:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/monthly_newsletter_as_a_thinking_tool/</guid><description>The easiest, very high ROI step is to simply open up a new Evernote document on the first of each month and title it &amp;ldquo;February 2018 Update&amp;rdquo; or whatever. Then just try to keep that tab open. You&amp;rsquo;ll find stuff to put in there. What I end up writing generally falls into a small number of categories:
Links to things that I think my friend would be interested in, with a bit of discussion of why I think it&amp;rsquo;s interesting.</description></item><item><title>Attention is Your Scarcest Resource</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/attention_is_your_scarcest_resource/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:46:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/attention_is_your_scarcest_resource/</guid><description>As a programmer, I tried to make sure that I was only ever working on one thing at a time. Even if I got stuck on that one thing—say I was blocked on waiting for a tech partner to give me API documentation—I’d let myself stay stuck instead of sliding off to work on something else.
In the short term, this made me less efficient, because I’d spend less time programming and more time staring vacantly at the ceiling.</description></item><item><title>Be Impatient</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/be_impatient/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:45:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/be_impatient/</guid><description> Being impatient is the best way to get faster at things. And across a surprising number of domains, being really fast correlates strongly with being effective.
TODOExpand with further quotes from article</description></item><item><title>Three Kinds of Non-Fiction Books</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/three_kinds_of_non_fiction_books/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:22:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/three_kinds_of_non_fiction_books/</guid><description>Narrative Narrative books are books that tell a story. Examples include biographies, memoirs, and histories.
Tree Tree books are books that lay out a framework of ideas. A good example is Daniel Kahneman&amp;rsquo;s Thinking: Fast and Slow, which lays out his life&amp;rsquo;s work — the entirety of behavioural economics — in a single book. (So an entire field, like a tree of knowledge, in one book. Geddit, geddit?</description></item><item><title>Career Moat</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/career_moat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:21:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/career_moat/</guid><description> A career moat is an individual’s ability to maintain competitive advantages over your competition (say, in the job market) in order to protect your long term prospects, your employability, and your ability to generate sufficient financial returns to support the life you want to live. Just like a medieval castle, the moat serves to protect those inside the fortress and their riches from outsiders.</description></item><item><title>Humans are not Automatically Strategic</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/humans_are_not_automatically_strategic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:11:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/humans_are_not_automatically_strategic/</guid><description>Why will a randomly chosen eight-year-old fail a calculus test? Because most possible answers are wrong, and there is no force to guide him to the correct answers. (There is no need to postulate a “fear of success”; most ways writing or not writing on a calculus test constitute failure, and so people, and rocks, fail calculus tests by default.)
Why do most of us, most of the time, choose to &amp;ldquo;pursue our goals&amp;rdquo; through routes that are far less effective than the routes we could find if we tried?</description></item><item><title>Learned Blankness</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/learned_blankness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:07:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/learned_blankness/</guid><description>Martin Seligman coined the term &amp;ldquo;learned helplessness&amp;rdquo; to describe a condition in which someone has learned to behave as though they were helpless. I think we need a term for learned helplessness about thinking (in a particular domain). I’ll call this “learned blankness”. Folks who fall prey to learned blankness may still take actions &amp;ndash; sometimes my students practiced the procedures again and again, hired a tutor, etc. But they do so as though carrying out rituals to an unknown god &amp;ndash; parts of them may be trying, but their “understand X” center has given up.</description></item><item><title>Productivity Notes from Sam Altman</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/productivity_notes_from_sam_altman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 08:43:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/productivity_notes_from_sam_altman/</guid><description>Notes It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how fast you move if it&amp;rsquo;s in a worthless direction. Picking the right thing to work on is the most important element of productivity and usually almost ignored.
The most impressive people I know have strong beliefs about the world, which is rare in the general population. If you find yourself always agreeing with whomever you last spoke with, that&amp;rsquo;s bad.
I make sure to leave enough time in my schedule to think about what to work on.</description></item><item><title>(a)</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 07:55:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/a/</guid><description>Summary Dead links are inevitable if your written content lives long enough online. Include archive links alongside links to off-domain content &amp;ldquo;(a)&amp;rdquo;.
Thoughts I like the idea of including an archive link when linking to off-domain content. It seems like something that I could automate through some &amp;ldquo;presubmit&amp;rdquo; step of the publishing process. I&amp;rsquo;ve looked around but haven&amp;rsquo;t found an addon/extension for any of the popular blogging solutions which provides an easy way to include such links.</description></item><item><title>Psychophysiologic Symptom Relief Therapy</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/psychophysiologic_symptom_relief_therapy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 06:31:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/psychophysiologic_symptom_relief_therapy/</guid><description>Psychophysiologic Symptom Relief Therapy (PSRT) is a program for pain relief first?detailed in Donnino et al. and makes use of Mindfulness-based Stress Reduction
Components of the Psychophysiologic Symptom Relief Therapy (PSRT) program PSRT is a treatment program designed for patients with non-specific chronic back pain. The intervention consists of a one-on-one interview with the investigator, group educational and skills-training sessions over a four-week period for approximately 1.5-2 hours per session twice per week, followed by an eight-week mindfulness-based stress reduction program plus one full- day session/retreat.</description></item><item><title>Mindfulness-based Stress Reduction</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/mindfulness_based_stress_reduction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 05:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/mindfulness_based_stress_reduction/</guid><description> &amp;hellip; an eight-week evidence-based program that offers secular, intensive mindfulness training to assist people with stress, anxiety, depression and pain.
Wikipedia
The program has been found to be effective. Some hospitals staff experts who offer a regularly-occurring class. Dave Potter offers a free version in his Palouse Mindfulness program.</description></item><item><title>Idea Queue</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/idea_queue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 15:30:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/idea_queue/</guid><description> My blog post authoring process with emacs, org-mode, ox-hugo, and org-roam. Thoughts on productivity, guilt, and free time as an illusion. My process for managing my Anki cards in Emacs.</description></item><item><title>At Least Two of the Same</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/at_least_two_of_the_same/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/at_least_two_of_the_same/</guid><description>I always do at least 2 of the same, so I can see where my work was intentional and where it was accidental.
For example When I do sets I make 2-4-6 of the same shape/size/color. They started out being cousins, then became sisters, now they are twins. Knowing I can form a shape with intention was important to me. It strengthened my skill.
BUT there is a place for &amp;lsquo;form-finding&amp;rsquo; which I think describes how you made these shapes you are showing us.</description></item><item><title>Polyphasic Sleep: 40 Day Trial Results</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/polyphasic_sleep_40_day_trial_results/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 12:15:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/polyphasic_sleep_40_day_trial_results/</guid><description>What would you do with another few hours every day? This was the thought that pulled me into attempting a polyphasic sleep schedule.
Note that I didn&amp;rsquo;t keep good notes while I was researching the intricacies of polyphasic sleep. There will be quite a few uncited claims.
Why Change My Sleep Schedule? In short: to live longer.
I expect to live for another 50.4 years1. I was getting an average of nine hours of sleep every night prior to stating this experiment.</description></item><item><title>The First Lesson</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the_first_lesson/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 12:44:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the_first_lesson/</guid><description> Muad&amp;rsquo;Dib learned rapidly because his first training was in how to learn. And the first lesson of all was the basic trust that he could learn. It&amp;rsquo;s shocking to find how many people do not believe they can learn, and how many more believe learning to be difficult. Muad&amp;rsquo;Dib knew that every experience carries its lesson.
Princess Irulan, Dune</description></item><item><title>Links</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/links/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/links/</guid><description>Links 2021 May Theory of Change by Aaron Swartz
A theory of change is the opposite of a theory of action &amp;mdash; it works backwards from the goal, in concrete steps, to figure out what you can do to achieve it. To develop a theory of change, you need to start at the end and repeatedly ask yourself, &amp;quot;Concretely, how does one achieve that?&amp;quot;
Cached Selves by Anna Salamon</description></item><item><title>Gmail in Emacs with mbsync and mu4e</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read-email-in-emacs-with-mbsync-isync-and-mu4e/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read-email-in-emacs-with-mbsync-isync-and-mu4e/</guid><description>This is a guide to setting up access to email from a Gmail account (eg: @gmail.com) within doom emacs using mu, mbsync (isync), and mu4e (mu for emacs).
You may have to complete additional steps if you are not using doom emacs, Gmail, or if your set-up differs from mine in other ways.
Prerequisites Please be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve completed these steps before continuing:
Required Software Install mbsync version &amp;gt;= 1.</description></item><item><title>Gmail in Emacs with notmuch and lieer</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read-email-from-gmail-with-notmuch-and-lieer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read-email-from-gmail-with-notmuch-and-lieer/</guid><description>This is a guide to setting up access to email (eg: @gmail.com) within doom emacs using notmuch and lieer.
You may have to complete additional steps if you are not using doom emacs or if your set-up differs from mine in other ways.
Prerequisites Please be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve completed these steps before continuing:
Required Software lieer
git clone https://github.com/gauteh/lieer.git cd lieer pip3 install -r requirements.txt notmuch</description></item><item><title>Create an OAuth2 Client ID</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/create-an-oauth2-client-id/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/create-an-oauth2-client-id/</guid><description>A short guide to creating an OAuth2 Client ID through the Google Cloud Console.
Create a new OAuth2 Client ID These steps are based on the steps outlined by ccrusius.
Navigate to the Cloud Console. Choose an existing project or create a new one. Select &amp;ldquo;APIs &amp;amp; Services&amp;rdquo; from the navigation menu. Select &amp;ldquo;Credentials&amp;rdquo;. Create new credentials of type &amp;ldquo;OAuth Client ID&amp;rdquo;. Choose application type &amp;ldquo;Other&amp;rdquo;. Choose a name for the client.</description></item><item><title>Tracking Time with Tasker and Google Calendar</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tracking-time-with-tasker-and-google-calendar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tracking-time-with-tasker-and-google-calendar/</guid><description>In the spirit of personal time tracking, I thought I would share my method as well. I&amp;rsquo;ll write a follow-up, or amend this post, with the relevant source code at some point.
I started tracking my time a few months ago so I could have data to back up questions about how much I time I was giving to studying, working, cooking, chores, friends, etc. The solutions I found for tracking personal time didn&amp;rsquo;t mesh with the way I wanted to track time:</description></item><item><title>Goals for 2021</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/goals-for-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/goals-for-2021/</guid><description>The unexamined life is not worth living, man.
These are vague goals, in no particular order, for myself in 2021. I think it would be helpful to break them down into shorter-term and specific goals. That&amp;rsquo;ll come later. For now&amp;hellip;
Give more time to the people in my life. Keep in touch with friends. Learn my working limit and respect it. Become more comfortable sitting quietly in a room alone.</description></item><item><title>Custom Anki Notes</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/custom-anki-notes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/custom-anki-notes/</guid><description>I use Anki to help myself remember the things I learn. Anki is flashcard software that integrates spaced repetition and active recall testing. I found creating cards, as well as managing existing cards, was easier after creating custom note types to represent specific information.
Most of my cards include a common field: Source. I like to keep track of where I found the information that went into the card, be that Wikipedia or a textbook or otherwise.</description></item></channel></rss>