<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>reference on Cash Weaver</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/categories/reference/</link><description>Recent content in reference on Cash Weaver</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 13:08:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cashweaver.com/categories/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anki - Powerful, Intelligent Flashcards</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ankipowerfulintelligentflashcards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 13:08:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ankipowerfulintelligentflashcards/</guid><description>(“Anki - Powerful, Intelligent Flashcards” n.d.)
A software solution for spaced repetition.
Anki is a program which makes remembering things easy. Because it&amp;rsquo;s a lot more efficient than traditional study methods, you can either greatly decrease your time spent studying, or greatly increase the amount you learn.
.csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Anki - Powerful, Intelligent Flashcards.” n.d. Accessed February 8, 2022. https://apps.ankiweb.net/.</description></item><item><title>Adam Zerner :: Writing to Think</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/zernerwritingthink/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 18:46:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/zernerwritingthink/</guid><description>Adam Zerner, (Zerner n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Zerner, Adam. n.d. “Writing to Think.” Accessed February 8, 2022. https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/SKQmvZMTY6zQf3Ktc/writing-to-think.</description></item><item><title>Julian Shapiro :: How to Punctuate</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/shapirohowpunctuate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:30:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/shapirohowpunctuate/</guid><description>Julian Shapiro, (Shapiro n.d.)
TODO Summary TODO Thoughts TODO Notes .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Shapiro, Julian. n.d. “How to Punctuate.” Accessed February 8, 2022. https://www.julian.com/blog/punctuation. TODO Incorporate points I agree with into Style Guide</description></item><item><title>Breck Yunits :: Write Thin to Write Fast</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/yunitswritethinwritefast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 08:20:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/yunitswritethinwritefast/</guid><description>Breck Yunits, (Yunits n.d.)
Summary Set your editor&amp;rsquo;s column width very low &amp;hellip; 36 characters for me, [your mileage may vary].
Thinner columns help you read faster. Writing speed is dominated by reading speed. If you read faster, you write faster.
Thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve seem content width discussed often when it comes to reading. A width of 72 characters comes to mind, though I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where I picked that up.</description></item><item><title>Tim Peck :: What Are the Three Types of Fun?</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/whatarethreetypesfun2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 08:09:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/whatarethreetypesfun2017/</guid><description>Tim Peck, (Peck 2017)
Summary Type Fun in the moment Fun when looking back 1 Yes Yes 2 No Yes 3 No No Thoughts Notes Type three fun is the sticking point for most people:
[&amp;hellip;] [I]t’s the type that makes most of us go crawling back to Type 1, and say, &amp;ldquo;The heck with Type 2, because it’s just too damned close to Type 3.</description></item><item><title>Eliezer Yudkowsky :: Tsuyoku Naritai! (I Want To Become Stronger)</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/yudkowskytsuyokunaritaiwant2007/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 08:06:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/yudkowskytsuyokunaritaiwant2007/</guid><description>Eliezer Yudkowsky, (Yudkowsky 2007)
TODO Summary TODO Thoughts Notes The most important thing is that there should be progress. So long as you keep moving forward you will reach your destination; but if you stop moving you will never reach it.
Tsuyoku naritai is Japanese. Tsuyoku is “strong”; naru is “becoming,” and the form naritai is “want to become.” Together it means, “I want to become stronger,” and it expresses a sentiment embodied more intensely in Japanese works than in any Western literature I’ve read.</description></item><item><title>Cedric Chin :: To Get Good, Go After The Metagame</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/chingetgoodgometagame2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 08:01:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/chingetgoodgometagame2020/</guid><description>Cedric Chin, (Chin 2020)
TODO Summary TODO Thoughts Notes Every sufficiently interesting game has a metagame above it. This is the game about the game. It is often called ‘the meta’.
Every sufficiently interesting domain in the world has a meta associated with it.
What is interesting about the meta is that metagames can only be played if you have mastered the basics of the domain.</description></item><item><title>Cedric Chin :: The Three Kinds of Non-Fiction Books</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/chinthreekindsnonfiction2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:36:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/chinthreekindsnonfiction2018/</guid><description>Cedric Chin, (Chin 2018)
Summary Thoughts Notes Narrative Narrative books are books that tell a story. Examples include biographies, memoirs, and histories.
Tree Tree books are books that lay out a framework of ideas. A good example is Daniel Kahneman&amp;rsquo;s Thinking: Fast and Slow, which lays out his life&amp;rsquo;s work — the entirety of behavioural economics — in a single book. (So an entire field, like a tree of knowledge, in one book.</description></item><item><title>Derek Sivers :: There's No Speed Limit</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/siverstherenospeed2009/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:34:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/siverstherenospeed2009/</guid><description>Derek Sivers, (Sivers 2009)
TODO Summary TODO Thoughts Notes Kimo&amp;rsquo;s high expectations set a new pace for me. He taught me that &amp;ldquo;the standard pace is for chumps&amp;rdquo; — that the system is designed so anyone can keep up. If you&amp;rsquo;re more driven than most people, you can do way more than anyone expects. And this principle applies to all of life, not just school.
.csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.</description></item><item><title>Andy Payne :: The Myth of the Myth of the 10x Programmer</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/paynemythmyth10xprogrammer2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:33:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/paynemythmyth10xprogrammer2020/</guid><description>Andy Payne, (Payne 2020)
Summary Thoughts This reminds me of a way of conceptualizing a &amp;ldquo;10x&amp;rdquo; programmer (though I no longer recall where I read the idea): 10x programmers are not 10x because they code/write/etc 10x faster; they&amp;rsquo;re 10x because they solve the big problems that a non-10x programmer cannot solve.
Notes I don’t know anyone 10x faster than their peers in solving well-defined programming problems.
&amp;hellip;
[H]ighly productive developers (10x or otherwise) are problem-solving at a much higher level.</description></item><item><title>James Altucher :: The Ultimate Guide for Becoming an Idea Machine</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ultimateguidebecomingideamachine2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:16:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ultimateguidebecomingideamachine2014/</guid><description>James Altucher, (NO_ITEM_DATA:UltimateGuideBecomingIdeaMachine2014)
Summary Thoughts Notes If I say, “write down ten ideas for books you can write” I bet you can easily write down four or five. I can write down four or five right now. But at six it starts to get hard. “Hmmm,” you think, “what else can I come up with?”
This is when the brain is sweating.
Note that when you exercise in the gym, your muscles don’t start to build until you break a sweat.</description></item><item><title>Walter Lippmann :: The Basic Problem of Democracy</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/lippmannbasicproblemdemocracy1919/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:13:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/lippmannbasicproblemdemocracy1919/</guid><description>Walter Lippman, (Lippmann 1919)
Summary A well written essay whose thesis, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit embarrassed to say, eludes me.
Thoughts I expect one could find gold in this essay but I think I will instead read, as one commenter recommended, &amp;ldquo;Goliath&amp;rdquo; by Matt Stoller.
Notes If we substitute the word indifference for the word liberty, we shall come much closer to the real intention that lies behind the classic argument.</description></item><item><title>Scott Alexander :: Socratic Grilling</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/alexandersocraticgrilling2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:03:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/alexandersocraticgrilling2020/</guid><description>Scott Alexander, (Alexander 2020)
Summary Thoughts TODO Notes One of the most important rationalist skills is “noticing your confusion”. But that depends on an even more important proto-skill of wanting things to make sense. If you lose that skill – if it stops bothering you and seeming like a problem when things don’t make sense to you – you will never notice your confusion and you will never become a good scientist or a good anything-else-that-requires-independent-thought.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia :: SMART Criteria</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/smartcriteria2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:59:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/smartcriteria2022/</guid><description>(“SMART Criteria” 2022)
SMART goals are:
Specific – target a specific area Measurable – quantify or at least suggest an indicator of progress Assignable – specify who will do it Realistic – state what results can realistically be achieved, given available resources Time-related – specify when the result(s) can be achieved .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“SMART Criteria.” 2022. Wikipedia, January. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=SMART_criteria&amp;#38;oldid=1067426737.</description></item><item><title>Michael W. Donnino et al. :: Psychophysiologic Symptom Relief Therapy for Chronic Back Pain: A Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/donninopsychophysiologicsymptomrelieftherapychronicbackpainpilotrandomizedcontrolledtrial2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:48:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/donninopsychophysiologicsymptomrelieftherapychronicbackpainpilotrandomizedcontrolledtrial2021/</guid><description>(Donnino et al. 2021)
Summary Thoughts Notes PSRT is a treatment program designed for patients with non-specific chronic back pain. The intervention consists of a one-on-one interview with the investigator, group educational and skills-training sessions over a four-week period for approximately 1.5-2 hours per session twice per week, followed by an eight-week mindfulness-based stress reduction program plus one full- day session/retreat. The course is delivered in small groups facilitated by a trained instructor.</description></item><item><title>Sam Altman :: Productivity</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/altmanproductivity2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:46:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/altmanproductivity2018/</guid><description>Sam Altman, (Altman 2018)
Summary Thoughts Notes It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how fast you move if it&amp;rsquo;s in a worthless direction. Picking the right thing to work on is the most important element of productivity and usually almost ignored.
The most impressive people I know have strong beliefs about the world, which is rare in the general population. If you find yourself always agreeing with whomever you last spoke with, that&amp;rsquo;s bad.</description></item><item><title>Valentine :: Noticing the Taste of Lotus</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/valentinenoticingtastelotus2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:33:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/valentinenoticingtastelotus2018/</guid><description>Michael Smith, (Valentine 2018)
Duncan Sabien sometimes talks about “lotus-eating”. He’s referring to a part of the Odyssey where they land on an island of “lotus-eaters”. It turns out that once you eat some of this kind of lotus, all you want to do is eat more. You stop caring about your other goals. The lotus just grabs your wants directly.
The idea of noticing the taste of lotus is closely related to mindfulness and attention.</description></item><item><title>Alexey Nikitin :: My least favorite Git commit</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/nikitinmyleastfavoritegitcommit2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:31:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/nikitinmyleastfavoritegitcommit2019/</guid><description>Alexey Nikitin, (Nikitin 2019)
Summary Thoughts See: Documenting Your Work
Notes The essay isn&amp;rsquo;t written in English. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Google Translate to read and quote.
Commit messages do not help to find problems and their causes
[&amp;hellip;] very often I cannot find the commit in which the change I need was made. First, on a line that works erroneously, there are usually several commits, and you need to look at everything.</description></item><item><title>David Thompson :: My Favourite Git Commit</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/thompsonmyfavouritegitcommit2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:26:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/thompsonmyfavouritegitcommit2019/</guid><description>David Thompson, (Thompson 2019)
Summary Thoughts See: Documenting Your Work
Notes Dan Carley&amp;rsquo;s commit in alphagov/govuk-puppet:
Convert template to US-ASCII to fix error I introduced some tests in a feature branch to match the contents of `/etc/nginx/router_routes.conf`. They worked fine when run with `bundle exec rake spec` or `bundle exec rspec modules/router/spec`. But when run as `bundle exec rake` each should block failed with: ArgumentError: invalid byte sequence in US-ASCII I eventually found that removing the `.</description></item><item><title>moridinamael :: The Monthly Newsletter as Thinking Tool</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/moridinamaelmonthlynewsletterthinking2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:19:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/moridinamaelmonthlynewsletterthinking2018/</guid><description>Matt Freeman, (moridinamael 2018)
Summary Thoughts Notes The easiest, very high ROI step is to simply open up a new Evernote document on the first of each month and title it &amp;ldquo;February 2018 Update&amp;rdquo; or whatever. Then just try to keep that tab open. You&amp;rsquo;ll find stuff to put in there. What I end up writing generally falls into a small number of categories:
Links to things that I think my friend would be interested in, with a bit of discussion of why I think it&amp;rsquo;s interesting.</description></item><item><title>Elizabeth J. Marsh, Andrew C. Butler :: Memory in Educational Settings</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/marshmemoryeducationalsettings2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 21:10:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/marshmemoryeducationalsettings2013/</guid><description>TODO_AUTHOR, (Marsh and Butler 2013)
Summary Retrieval or re-experiencing a memory will increase retention. Studying should be somewhat difficult; neither too difficult that the subject is unable to overcome the challenge, nor too easy. The difficulty is desirable feature of the process of studying in that the difficulty improves retention. One does not need to be aware of the specific benefits of a study method to benefit from them.</description></item><item><title>Neel Nanda :: Meaningful Rest</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/nandameaningfulrest/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 20:52:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/nandameaningfulrest/</guid><description>Neel Nanda, (Nanda n.d.)
TODO Summary TODO Thoughts Notes An exercise: Set a 5 minute timer, and list the things you want to do when you feel tired and low-energy. Then, set another 5 minute timer, and list the things you feel rejuvenated after having done - the things you like doing when low-energy.
If you’re anything like me, these lists are basically disjoint!
Most situations in my life have a default response, and that takes no effort to follow.</description></item><item><title>Kamran Ahmed :: Levels of Seniority</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ahmedlevelsseniority/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 20:50:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ahmedlevelsseniority/</guid><description>Kamran Ahmed, (Ahmed n.d.)
Summary The most important traits that you need to have in order to step up in your career are: not settling with mediocrity, having an open mindset, being humble, learning from your mistakes, working on the challenging problems and having an opportunity mindset rather than a complaining one.
Thoughts Notes I have seen fresh graduates having no industry experience get up to speed quickly and producing work of a Senior Engineer and I have seen Senior developers labeled &amp;ldquo;senior&amp;rdquo; merely because of their age and &amp;ldquo;years of experience&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Stephen Kuenzli :: Key Practices for Achieving Large Professional Goals</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/kuenzlikeypracticesachievinglargeprofessionalgoals2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 20:49:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/kuenzlikeypracticesachievinglargeprofessionalgoals2019/</guid><description>Stephen Kuenzli, (Kuenzli 2019)
Summary I attribute much of my success in 2019 to the practices of:
writing to develop my thoughts learning to focus I wrote a lot in 2019 &amp;hellip; This practice of writing resulted in a couple major changes:
I now use writing as a primary mechanism to develop my thoughts on a subject Writing is now a healthy habit for my professional skills and business Kuenzli mentions that they &amp;ldquo;really learned how to focus and extract much more value out of the time I have available&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Anna Salamon :: Humans Are Not Automatically Strategic</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/annasalamonhumansarenot2010/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 20:45:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/annasalamonhumansarenot2010/</guid><description>Anna Salamon, (NO_ITEM_DATA:annasalamonHumansAreNot2010)
Summary Thoughts Notes Why will a randomly chosen eight-year-old fail a calculus test? Because most possible answers are wrong, and there is no force to guide him to the correct answers. (There is no need to postulate a “fear of success”; most ways writing or not writing on a calculus test constitute failure, and so people, and rocks, fail calculus tests by default.)
Why do most of us, most of the time, choose to &amp;ldquo;pursue our goals&amp;rdquo; through routes that are far less effective than the routes we could find if we tried?</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia :: Zettelkasten</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/zettelkasten2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 18:03:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/zettelkasten2021/</guid><description>(“Zettelkasten” 2021)
A zettelkasten is a personal knowledge management system consisting of densely interlinked (usually) short notes. The system was originally implemented with index cards. Nowadays there are digital solutions.
.csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Zettelkasten.” 2021. Wikipedia, December. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Zettelkasten&amp;#38;oldid=1060558761.</description></item><item><title>S Keshav :: How to Read a Paper</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/keshavhowreadpaper/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/keshavhowreadpaper/</guid><description>(Keshav, n.d.)
Notes .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Keshav, S. n.d. “How to Read a Paper.”</description></item><item><title>Jason Fried :: Habits Always Form</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/friedhabitsalwaysform2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:53:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/friedhabitsalwaysform2019/</guid><description>Jason Fried, (Fried 2019)
Habits are always forming. No matter what you do, you’re also forming habits too. Keep that in mind with whatever you do.
When we talk about habits, we generally talk about learning good habits. Or forming good habits. Both of these outcomes suggest we can end up with the habits we want. And technically we can! But most of the habits we have are habits we ended up with after years of unconscious behavior.</description></item><item><title>Anna Salamon :: Learned Blankness</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/annasalamonlearnedblankness2011/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:49:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/annasalamonlearnedblankness2011/</guid><description>Anna Salamon, (Salamon 2011)
Summary Thoughts Notes Martin Seligman coined the term &amp;ldquo;learned helplessness&amp;rdquo; to describe a condition in which someone has learned to behave as though they were helpless. I think we need a term for learned helplessness about thinking (in a particular domain). I’ll call this “learned blankness”. Folks who fall prey to learned blankness may still take actions &amp;ndash; sometimes my students practiced the procedures again and again, hired a tutor, etc.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia :: Law of Triviality</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/lawtriviality2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:47:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/lawtriviality2021/</guid><description>(“Law of Triviality” 2021)
[&amp;hellip;] people [&amp;hellip;] typically give disproportionate weight to trivial issues.
Also known as &amp;ldquo;bike-shedding&amp;rdquo;.
.csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Law of Triviality.” 2021. Wikipedia, December. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Law_of_triviality&amp;#38;oldid=1058709714.</description></item><item><title>Paul Graham :: How to Write Usefully</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/howwriteusefully/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:42:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/howwriteusefully/</guid><description>Paul Graham, (NO_ITEM_DATA:HowWriteUsefully)
Summary A useful essay is one which is novel, correct, important, and strong:
A novel essay communicates a &amp;ldquo;new thing&amp;rdquo; (point of view, fact, opinion, etc) to at least some of its audience. A correct essay is factually accurate; insofar as is possible. An important essay matters to at least some people. You can measure it by the product of the number of people for which your points matter and how much it matters to those people.</description></item><item><title>Scott Alexander :: For, Then Against, High-Saturated-Fat Diets</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/alexanderthenhighsaturatedfatdiets2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:33:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/alexanderthenhighsaturatedfatdiets2020/</guid><description>Scott Alexander, (Alexander 2020)
Summary Thoughts Perfectionism A sentence in the beginning of the essay stood out to me:
I’ve been told that another blog called Hyperlipid has a deeper investigation, but I’ve only scratched the surface of them. [&amp;hellip;] I don’t claim to fully understand these people and I apologize for any misrepresentations I might be making. But the short version is: they all agree that everything went wrong when we switched from saturated to unsaturated fat.</description></item><item><title>Cedric Chin :: Expertise Is 'Just' Pattern Matching</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/chinexpertisejustpatternmatching2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 16:53:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/chinexpertisejustpatternmatching2020/</guid><description>Cedric Chin, (Chin 2020)
Summary Expertise is just pattern matching. In other words, being an expert at something is equivalent to being really good at (1) recognizing situations and (2) knowing how to respond to those situations. Simple, right?
Notes [&amp;hellip;] the notion that &amp;lsquo;expertise is simply pattern-matching’ [&amp;hellip;] follows naturally from two other ideas that I’ve covered extensively on Commonplace over the past year.
The first idea is the ‘recognition-primed decision making’ model developed by psychologist Gary Klein and his collaborators, working in the US military and with expert firefighters and NICU nurses.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia :: Festina Lente</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/festinalente2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 16:50:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/festinalente2022/</guid><description>(“Festina Lente” 2022)
[&amp;hellip;] a classical adage and oxymoron meaning &amp;ldquo;make haste slowly&amp;rdquo; (sometimes rendered in English as &amp;ldquo;more haste, less speed&amp;rdquo;).
.csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Festina Lente.” 2022. Wikipedia, February. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Festina_lente&amp;#38;oldid=1070080472.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia :: Dunning-Kruger Effect</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/dunningkrugereffect2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 16:07:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/dunningkrugereffect2022/</guid><description>(“DunningKruger Effect” 2022)
[T]he cognitive bias whereby people with low ability at a task overestimate their ability. Some researchers also include in their definition the opposite effect for high performers: their tendency to underestimate their skills.
.csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“DunningKruger Effect.” 2022. Wikipedia, February. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect&amp;#38;oldid=1070028100.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia :: Desirable Difficulty</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/desirabledifficulty2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 16:03:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/desirabledifficulty2022/</guid><description>(“Desirable Difficulty” 2022)
A desirable difficulty is a learning task that requires a considerable but desirable amount of effort, thereby improving long-term performance.
Examples include:
Retrieval practice (eg: flashcards) Spacing and interleaving (eg: Spaced Repetition) To determine whether a difficulty is desirable, use the following three guidelines:
The processing at encoding should be the same as the processing at retrieval. The processing at encoding should be the same as the processing during practice.</description></item><item><title>Dan Moore :: Cultivate the Skill of Undivided Attention, or "Deep Work"</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/mooredscultivateskillundividedattentiondeepwork2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/mooredscultivateskillundividedattentiondeepwork2019/</guid><description>Dan Moore, (mooreds 2019)
Summary Thoughts Notes Here’s the list of topics that I’d need to dedicate significant time to, in order to close the gap between me and the senior developers on our team, that I’ve encountered in my last two days of work:
Breaking complex unknowns into simpler unknowns that can be further split into individual tickets Adding tests to complex, legacy code, to guide further refactoring of said code.</description></item><item><title>Cedric Chin :: What Is a Career Moat?</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/chinwhatcareermoat2018/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 15:53:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/chinwhatcareermoat2018/</guid><description>Cedric Chin, (Chin 2018)
Summary Thoughts Notes A career moat is an individual’s ability to maintain competitive advantages over your competition (say, in the job market) in order to protect your long term prospects, your employability, and your ability to generate sufficient financial returns to support the life you want to live. Just like a medieval castle, the moat serves to protect those inside the fortress and their riches from outsiders.</description></item><item><title>James Stuber :: Master Boring Fundamentals 01: Boring Is Fun</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/masterboringfundamentals01boringfun/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 15:51:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/masterboringfundamentals01boringfun/</guid><description>James Stuber, (NO_ITEM_DATA:MasterBoringFundamentals01BoringFun)
Summary Thoughts Notes We go to incredible lengths to avoid actions that we know are good for us.
Ski enthusiast Tim Peck shows us that there are actually two types of fun:
Type 1 Fun: Pure fun, untarnished by setbacks Type 2 Fun: Suffering now; fun after the fact, in retrospect Not Fun: Not fun now, not fun later, “I’m never doing that again”</description></item><item><title>Scott Alexander :: Book Review: The Seven Principles For Making Marriage Work</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/alexanderbookreviewsevenprinciplesmakingmarriagework2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 15:43:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/alexanderbookreviewsevenprinciplesmakingmarriagework2020/</guid><description>Scott Alexander, (Alexander 2020), The Seven Principles for Making Marriage Work
Summary The legend of John Gottman&amp;rsquo;s marriage counselling success isn&amp;rsquo;t supported by the underlying research at a statistical level; however, the techniques he advocates may help anyway.
Thoughts I enjoyed the personality that this essay had. A more direct essay could have started out by stating the problems with Gottman&amp;rsquo;s research. You could argue this essay buried the lede. That said, I enjoyed reading the piece.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia :: Bloom's Taxonomy</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/bloomtaxonomy2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 15:38:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/bloomtaxonomy2022/</guid><description>(“Bloom’s Taxonomy” 2022)
Bloom&amp;rsquo;s taxonomy is a set of three hierarchical models used to classify educational learning objectives into levels of complexity and specificity. &amp;hellip; The cognitive domain list has been the primary focus of most traditional education and is frequently used to structure curriculum learning objectives, assessments and activities.
(“Bloom’s Taxonomy” 2022)
In order from least complex to most complex:
Knowledge Comprehension Application Analysis Synthesis Evaluation Anderson proposed proposed a revision of Bloom&amp;rsquo;s cognitive taxomomy (in order from least complex to most complex):</description></item><item><title>Milan Griffes :: (A)</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/griffes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 13:12:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/griffes/</guid><description>Milan Griffes, (Griffes n.d.)
Summary Dead links are inevitable if your written content lives long enough online. Include archive links alongside links to off-domain content &amp;ldquo;(a)&amp;rdquo;.
Thoughts I like the idea of including an archive link when linking to off-domain content. It seems like something that I could automate through some &amp;ldquo;presubmit&amp;rdquo; step of the publishing process. I&amp;rsquo;ve looked around but haven&amp;rsquo;t found an addon/extension for any of the popular blogging solutions which provides an easy way to include such links.</description></item></channel></rss>