<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>reference on Cash Weaver</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/categories/reference/</link><description>Recent content in reference on Cash Weaver</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 08:51:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cashweaver.com/categories/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jim Hefferon | Linear Algebra</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/jim-hefferon-linear-algebra/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 08:51:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/jim-hefferon-linear-algebra/</guid><description>Jim Hefferon, (Hefferon 2020)
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Hefferon, Jim. 2020. Linear Algebra. S.l.: ORTHOGONAL PUBLISHING L3C. https://gitlab.com/jim.hefferon/linear-algebra.</description></item><item><title>Betty Miller Unterberger | Power Politics and Statecraft: The World According to Kissinger</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/betty-miller-unterberger-power-politics-and-statecraft-the-world-according-to-kissinger/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 11:03:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/betty-miller-unterberger-power-politics-and-statecraft-the-world-according-to-kissinger/</guid><description>Betty Miller Unterberger, (Unterberger 1995)
Notes Kissinger&amp;rsquo;s Diplomacy is a masterful, brilliant and provocative account of world politics and American foreign policy from Cardinal Richelieu to the end of the Cold War. Its title, however is somewhat deceptive, because it is more than just an analysis of the tactics and techniques practiced in the conduct of international diplomacy. Diplomacy is old-fashioned diplomatic history which concentrates on the grand strategy, leadership, and philosophy of the great power relationships.</description></item><item><title>Citations Needed | News Brief: Biden's Dictator Tour and the Tedium of Our Human Rights Concerns Theater</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/citations-needed-news-brief-bidens-dictator-tour-and-the-tedium-of-our-human-rights-concerns-theater/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 18:27:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/citations-needed-news-brief-bidens-dictator-tour-and-the-tedium-of-our-human-rights-concerns-theater/</guid><description>Citations Needed, (Citations Needed 2022)
Summary Media Spin regarding President Biden&amp;rsquo;s visit to Saudi Arabia and meeting with Mohammed bin Salman as reluctantly performed or as a necessary evil Carry water for the underlying (Realpolitik) truth: Biden, and United States foreign policy in general dating back to well before Biden, engage willingly with Saudi Arabia. The purpose of the media spin is to provide a narrative for liberals to latch on to which explains why the United States is doing bad things, engaging with bad people, etc.</description></item><item><title>Julia Evans | So You Want to Be a Wizard</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/julia-evans-so-you-want-to-be-a-wizard/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 17:09:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/julia-evans-so-you-want-to-be-a-wizard/</guid><description>Julia Evans, (Evans n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes Wizard skills Understand your systems Related: Nelson Elhage | Computers Can Be Understood
Ask great questions Read the code Debug like a wizard Write down a design Understand the big picture References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Evans, Julia. n.d. “So You Want to Be a Wizard.” Julia Evans. Accessed July 22, 2022. https://jvns.ca/blog/so-you-want-to-be-a-wizard/.</description></item><item><title>Citations Needed</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/citations-needed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 11:10:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/citations-needed/</guid><description> A podcast on the media, power, PR and the history of bullshit.
Hosted by Nima Shirazi and Adam Johnson.
@CitationsPod References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}</description></item><item><title>Aaron Bastani | Fully Automated Luxury Communism: A Manifesto</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/aaron-bastani-fully-automated-luxury-communism-a-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 10:11:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/aaron-bastani-fully-automated-luxury-communism-a-manifesto/</guid><description>Aaron Bastani, (Bastani 2019)
Summary Original formalization of the concept of Fully Automated Luxury Communism.
Thoughts Notes References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Bastani, Aaron. 2019. Fully Automated Luxury Communism: A Manifesto. London ; New York: Verso.</description></item><item><title>Upstream</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/upstream/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 09:53:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/upstream/</guid><description> UNLEARN EVERYTHING YOU THOUGHT YOU KNEW ABOUT ECONOMICS
Radical ideas and inspiring stories for a just transition to a more beautiful and equitable world
(“Upstream Podcast” n.d.)
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Upstream Podcast.” n.d. Upstream-Podcast. Accessed July 21, 2022. https://www.upstreampodcast.org.</description></item><item><title>Upstream | Fully Automated Luxury Communism</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/upstream-fully-automated-luxury-communism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 09:40:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/upstream-fully-automated-luxury-communism/</guid><description>Upstream, (Upstream 2022)
Summary A discussion of Fully Automated Luxury Communism.
Notes [Della Z Duncan]
And so what about this term, fully automated luxury communism? How might you introduce that to someone who&amp;rsquo;s never heard of the term like, what might you say by way of introduction?
[Eric Wycoff Rogers]
Yeah, I would say essentially, it&amp;rsquo;s a position that insists that with the advent of automation, and robotization &amp;ndash; in other words, machines doing much of the work without human assistance or with as little human assistance as possible &amp;ndash; our society should leave most work to robots to produce abundance; that you can get away from a scarcity oriented economy towards an abundance oriented economy, and that we should equitably distribute what&amp;rsquo;s produced in that economic system in some kind of a post capitalist economy where everyone is taken care of no matter what.</description></item><item><title>Adolph Reed Jr | Nothing Left: The Past Is Always Present: Examining Quotidian Life under Jim Crow to Reveal Its Structures</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/adolph-reed-jr-nothing-left-the-past-is-always-present-examining-quotidian-life-under-jim-crow-to-reveal-its-structures/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 12:37:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/adolph-reed-jr-nothing-left-the-past-is-always-present-examining-quotidian-life-under-jim-crow-to-reveal-its-structures/</guid><description>Adolph Reed, (Reed 2014)
The left has no place it wants to go References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Reed, Adolph. 2014. “Nothing Left: The Past Is Always Present: Examining Quotidian Life under Jim Crow to Reveal Its Structures Read More.” Harper’s Magazine March 2014 (March). https://harpers.org/archive/2014/03/nothing-left-2/.</description></item><item><title>Ian Danskin | I Hate Mondays</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-i-hate-mondays/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 09:29:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-i-hate-mondays/</guid><description>Ian Danskin, (Danskin 2020)
This is an entry in the Alt-right Playbook.
Summary I hate mondays is an embrace of coping strategies and a refusal to address a problem stemming from the belief that the problem is unfixable.
Notes [&amp;hellip;] conservative thinks about people dying of preventable illnesses, school shootings, and back alley abortions the way you think about Mondays.
The conservative mindset tends to sort things into binaries with no room for scale.</description></item><item><title>Ian Danskin | Always a Bigger Fish</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-always-a-bigger-fish/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 08:54:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-always-a-bigger-fish/</guid><description>Ian Danskin, (Danskin 2019)
This is an entry in the Alt-right Playbook.
Summary Conservatives tend to think in hierarchies &amp;ndash; like a capitalist &amp;ndash; while liberals tend to think democratically &amp;ndash; like an egalitarian.
Notes See, when you talk to your conservative friend, you operate as though you have the same base assumptions: belief in democracy, &amp;ldquo;do unto others,&amp;rdquo; etc. etc. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t believe your friend shared these assumptions, you&amp;rsquo;d basically be calling him a fascist or a sadist.</description></item><item><title>Ian Danskin | The Card Says Moops</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-the-card-says-moops/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 08:25:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-the-card-says-moops/</guid><description>Ian Danskin, (Danskin 2019)
This is an entry in the Alt-right Playbook.
Summary Performative irony (see For the lulz) for the dual goals of winning arguments and obfuscating your true beliefs. That is, pretending (and possibly believing, at least at some level) that you just want to watch the world burn and the hiding, from others and yourself, the fact that you only ever seem to go after the Left and what the targets of your ire imply about your underlying beliefs.</description></item><item><title>Ian Danskin | The Death of a Euphemism</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-the-death-of-a-euphemism/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 20:19:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-the-death-of-a-euphemism/</guid><description>Ian Danskin, (Danskin 2018)
This is an entry in the Alt-right Playbook.
Summary Politicians only let a euphemism die when they don&amp;rsquo;t need it anymore.
[&amp;hellip;]
To the Far Right, a euphemism is like a calf: something to be brought into this world or inherited, removed from its original context, raised to adolescence, and then slaughtered when the time is right. Historically, the first sign that things are about to get a lot worse for minorities is when the racism stops being euphemistic.</description></item><item><title>Ian Danskin | The Ship of Theseus</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-the-ship-of-theseus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 20:03:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-the-ship-of-theseus/</guid><description>Ian Danskin, (Danskin 2018)
This is an entry in the Alt-right Playbook.
Summary How many words can you change in an argument until it&amp;rsquo;s not the same argument anymore?
Notes Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re bouncing around Twitter - a damn fool thing to do, but who am I to judge? - and you come across someone claiming &amp;ldquo;[Public Figure X] doxxed me.&amp;rdquo;
You&amp;rsquo;re thinking, &amp;ldquo;Oh no, I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Public Figure X!</description></item><item><title>Bob Altemeyer | The Authoritarians</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/bob-altemeyer-the-authoritarians/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 19:12:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/bob-altemeyer-the-authoritarians/</guid><description>Robert Altemeyer, (Altemeyer, n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes [&amp;hellip;] authoritarian followers place &amp;ldquo;being normal&amp;rdquo; substantially higher than most people do.
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Altemeyer, Bob. n.d. The Authoritarians. http://theauthoritarians.org.</description></item><item><title>Ian Danskin | Mainstreaming</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-mainstreaming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 18:55:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-mainstreaming/</guid><description>Ian Danskin, (Danskin 2018)
This is an entry in the Alt-right Playbook.
Summary Mainstreaming is the game of moving a concept from fringe to normal. It&amp;rsquo;s like a hammer in that a hammer is morally neutral and acquires a moral balance through use.
Thoughts Notes [&amp;hellip;] two of the most powerful tools for making any marginalized group less marginalized are Language and Visibility.
[&amp;hellip;]
[&amp;hellip;] as a fringe group becomes more visible, and their language becomes commonplace, their presence in society starts to seem normal.</description></item><item><title>Ian Danskin | Never Play Defense</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-never-play-defense/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 17:23:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-never-play-defense/</guid><description>Ian Danskin, (Danskin 2017)
This is an entry in the Alt-right Playbook.
Summary You can convince an audience that you&amp;rsquo;re winning an argument, or at least plant doubts in their head, by holding an offensive posture. Display the outward signs of winning &amp;ndash; confidence, always have a comeback, speak in soundbites, attack attack attack &amp;ndash; and the audience may think that you won even if your opponent refutes your argument.</description></item><item><title>Alt-right Playbook</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/alt-right-playbook/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 16:33:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/alt-right-playbook/</guid><description>The Alt-right Playbook is a series produced by Ian Danskin which discusses rhetorical techniques employed by the alt-right. It&amp;rsquo;s primary focus is on building a common language to describe patterns he, and others, observe in the alt-right.
While Danskin hasn&amp;rsquo;t formally proposed solutions or a counter-playbook, I have extracted some ideas from the Alt-right Playbook:
Speak directly to your audience; don&amp;rsquo;t validate terrible ideas by platforming them to your audience or by debating/etc Imagine others complexly Pursue egalitarian policies and structures of governance Prefer the Duck test to believing people at their word</description></item><item><title>Ian Danskin | Control the Conversation</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-control-the-conversation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 16:31:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ian-danskin-control-the-conversation/</guid><description>Ian Danskin, (Danskin 2017)
This is an entry in the Alt-right Playbook.
Summary Broadly, controlling the conversation is about making people talk about what you want them to talk about. More specifically, it&amp;rsquo;s about what you make them talk about. Structure debate, conversation, etc, based on the idea that the goal is to win. Move the goalposts while also redefining the rules by which you win the underlying game.
Notes [&amp;hellip;] every one of these bad arguments is a subtle attempt to change the subject.</description></item><item><title>Scott Alexander | I Can Tolerate Anything Except The Outgroup</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-i-can-tolerate-anything-except-the-outgroup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 20:41:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-i-can-tolerate-anything-except-the-outgroup/</guid><description>Scott Alexander, (Alexander 2014)
Summary A meditation on what it means to be tolerant. In short: tolerance and forgiveness aren&amp;rsquo;t easy and if they feel easy then you&amp;rsquo;re likely not actually tolerating or forgiving but rather remarking &amp;ldquo;No harm done.&amp;rdquo;
Thoughts Tolerance of intolerance Regarding the bit about Brendan Eich1:
Think of Brendan Eich as a member of a tiny religious minority surrounded by people who hate that minority. Suddenly firing him doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem very noble.</description></item><item><title>Matt Eding | Sparse Matrices</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/matt-eding-sparse-matrices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 18:33:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/matt-eding-sparse-matrices/</guid><description>TODO_AUTHOR, (Eding n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Eding, Matt. n.d. “Sparse Matrices.” Accessed June 22, 2022. https://matteding.github.io/2019/04/25/sparse-matrices/.</description></item><item><title>Albert Camus, Justin O'Brien | The Myth of Sisyphus and Other Essays</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/albert-camus-justin-obrien-the-myth-of-sisyphus-and-other-essays/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 12:32:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/albert-camus-justin-obrien-the-myth-of-sisyphus-and-other-essays/</guid><description>Albert Camus, (Camus and O’Brien 1991)
Summary Thoughts Notes One must imagine Sisyphus happy References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Camus, Albert, and Justin O’Brien. 1991. The Myth of Sisyphus and Other Essays. New York: Vintage Books. http://banq.lib.overdrive.com/ContentDetails.htm?id=83022612-B2C3-4305-BDB3-21C18D2A1763.</description></item><item><title>Amygdala Hijack</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/amygdala-hijack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 09:56:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/amygdala-hijack/</guid><description> An amygdala hijack is an emotional response that is immediate, overwhelming, and out of measure with the actual stimulus because it has triggered a much more significant emotional threat.
(“Amygdala Hijack” 2022)
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Amygdala Hijack.” 2022. Wikipedia, February. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Amygdala_hijack&amp;#38;oldid=1070742839.</description></item><item><title>Nick Bostrom | The Fable of the Dragon Tyrant</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/nick-bostrom-the-fable-of-the-dragon-tyrant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 20:17:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/nick-bostrom-the-fable-of-the-dragon-tyrant/</guid><description>Nick Bostrom, (Bostrom 2005)
Once upon a time, the planet was tyrannised by a giant dragon. The dragon stood taller than the largest cathedral, and it was covered with thick black scales. Its red eyes glowed with hate, and from its terrible jaws flowed an incessant stream of evil smelling yellowish green slime. It demanded from humankind a blood curdling tribute: to satisfy its enormous appetite, ten thousand men and women had to be delivered every evening at the onset of dark to the foot of the mountain where the dragon tyrant lived.</description></item><item><title>James F. Kile, Donald J. Little, Samir Shah | Busy Person Patterns</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/james-f.-kile-donald-j.-little-samir-shah-busy-person-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 18:07:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/james-f.-kile-donald-j.-little-samir-shah-busy-person-patterns/</guid><description>(Kile, Little, and Shah 2006)
Summary Thoughts Notes Skeleton Table of Contents Busy Person Patterns – An Introduction Just Start You have a task that cannot wait until you have all the information about it to begin. It may be time sensitive, you may have a deadline, or part of the task may be to identify its parts. Most important, you feel internal or external pressure to begin and have some level of confidence about the task&amp;rsquo;s overall direction.</description></item><item><title>Laura Taylor | Git + Google Drive = Simple Git Host</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/laura-taylor-git-google-drive-simple-git-host/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 08:20:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/laura-taylor-git-google-drive-simple-git-host/</guid><description>Laura Taylor, (Taylor 2021)
Mount Google Drive locally
Linux: I prefer rclone Windows: Google Drive Mac: Google Drive Navigate to your local git repository you&amp;rsquo;d like to host on Google Drive
Create a bare git clone:
git clone --bare \ . \ PATH_TO_GDRIVE/.../PROJECT_NAME.git Example:
git clone --bare . /mnt/gdrive/projects/addon.git Add this bare repository as a remote:
git remote add \ REMOTE_NAME \ PATH_TO_GDRIVE/.</description></item><item><title>The Onion | `No Way To Prevent This,' Says Only Nation Where This Regularly Happens</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the-onion-no-way-to-prevent-this-says-only-nation-where-this-regularly-happens/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 14:31:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the-onion-no-way-to-prevent-this-says-only-nation-where-this-regularly-happens/</guid><description>(“`No Way To Prevent This,’ Says Only Nation Where This Regularly Happens” n.d.)
VIRGINIA BEACH, VA—In the hours following a violent rampage in Virginia in which a lone attacker killed 12 individuals and injured four others, citizens living in the only country where this kind of mass killing routinely occurs reportedly concluded Wednesday that there was no way to prevent the massacre from taking place. &amp;ldquo;This was a terrible tragedy, but sometimes these things just happen and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing anyone can do to stop them,&amp;rdquo; said Michigan resident Mark Butler, echoing sentiments expressed by tens of millions of individuals who reside in a nation where over half of the world&amp;rsquo;s deadliest mass shootings have occurred in the past 50 years and whose citizens are 20 times more likely to die of gun violence than those of other developed nations.</description></item><item><title>Robin Hanson | The Age of Em: Work, Love, and Life When Robots Rule the Earth</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/robin-hanson-the-age-of-em-work-love-and-life-when-robots-rule-the-earth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 09:05:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/robin-hanson-the-age-of-em-work-love-and-life-when-robots-rule-the-earth/</guid><description>Robin Hanson, (Hanson 2016)
Summary Thoughts Notes References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Hanson, Robin. 2016. The Age of Em: Work, Love, and Life When Robots Rule the Earth. First Edition. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</description></item><item><title>Joseph Gentle | Three Tribes of Programming</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/joseph-gentle-three-tribes-of-programming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 10:06:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/joseph-gentle-three-tribes-of-programming/</guid><description>Joseph Gentle, (Gentle 2017)
Summary Programs, obviously, hold all of these properties. But I think there&amp;rsquo;s fundamentally 3 architypes of programmers, divided by which ideals we hold in highest esteem:
You are a poet and a mathematician. Programming is your poetry You are a hacker. You make hardware dance to your tune You are a maker. You build things for people to use We self-select into communities of our peers based on these ideals.</description></item><item><title>Scott Alexander | Meditations On Moloch</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-meditations-on-moloch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 20:30:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-meditations-on-moloch/</guid><description>Scott Alexander, (Alexander 2014)
Summary Systems compel the individuals within them to act within the rules of the system rather than by a globally optimal set of rules.
Related:
Tragedy of the Commons Notes I See Howl.
A lot of the commentators say Moloch represents capitalism. This is definitely a piece of it, even a big piece. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite fit. Capitalism, whose fate is a cloud of sexless hydrogen?</description></item><item><title>Dave Orr | Parenting Rules</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/dave-orr-parenting-rules/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 18:52:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/dave-orr-parenting-rules/</guid><description>(Orr n.d.)
Summary If I had to sum all these up, it would be this: raise kids for the long term. The reasoning behind all these choices is that we want to produce competent capable adults, and solving short term in-the-moment issues, while important, isn&amp;rsquo;t the goal.
Thoughts Notes Never lie If kids ask a question and they aren&amp;rsquo;t ready to hear the answer, just tell them that.</description></item><item><title>Bob Black | The Abolition of Work</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/bob-black-the-abolition-of-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 16:25:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/bob-black-the-abolition-of-work/</guid><description>Bob Black, (Black n.d.)
Summary We &amp;mdash; humans &amp;mdash; should abolish forced labor and replace it, and related systems, with un-forced labor: play.
Thoughts The essay is more focused on goals rather than the means with which we could achieve those goals. The way of organizing global society described here could be a north star for humanity over the next 200-500 years as we grow into post-scarcity.
Black proposes converting work to play.</description></item><item><title>Scott Alexander | Should You Reverse Any Advice You Hear?</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-should-you-reverse-any-advice-you-hear/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 07:31:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-should-you-reverse-any-advice-you-hear/</guid><description>Scott Alexander, (Alexander 2014)
Summary You&amp;rsquo;re more likely to hear things you agree with or that are, broadly speaking, aligned with your world-view. Therefore, you&amp;rsquo;re likely to over-index on a certain flavor of advice. You may benefit from considering the reverse of the piece of advice.
Thoughts A simple bit of metacognitive advice which I&amp;rsquo;d like to integrate into my daily life.
Notes Advice Reverse You need to stop being so hard on yourself, remember you are your own worst critic Stop making excuses for yourself, you will never be able to change until you admit you&amp;rsquo;ve hit bottom You need to remember that the government can&amp;rsquo;t solve all problems and that some regulations are counterproductive You need to remember that the free market can&amp;rsquo;t solve all problems and that some regulations are necessary You need to pay more attention to your diet or you&amp;rsquo;ll end up very unhealthy You need to pay less attention to your weight or you&amp;rsquo;ll end up in a spiral of shame and self-loathing and at risk of eating disorders You need to be more conscious of how your actions in social situations can make other people uncomfortable and violate their boundaries You need to overcome your social phobia by realizing that most interactions go well and that probably talking to people won&amp;rsquo;t always make them hate you and cause you to be ostracized forever You need to be less selfish and more considerate of the needs of others You can&amp;rsquo;t live for others all the time, you need to remember you deserve to be happy as well Follow your dreams, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be working forever at a job you hate Your dream of becoming a professional cosplayer may not be the best way to ensure a secure future for your family, go into petroleum engineering instead It&amp;rsquo;s much easier to join a group that celebrates your natural proclivities than one that demands you fight against them.</description></item><item><title>Ben Kuhn | In Defense of Blub Studies</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ben-kuhn-in-defense-of-blub-studies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 05:25:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ben-kuhn-in-defense-of-blub-studies/</guid><description>Ben Kuhn, (Kuhn n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Kuhn, Ben. n.d. “In Defense of Blub Studies.” Benkuhn.Net. Accessed March 12, 2022. https://www.benkuhn.net/blub/.</description></item><item><title>Nelson Elhage | Computers Can Be Understood</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/nelson-elhage-computers-can-be-understood/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 04:56:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/nelson-elhage-computers-can-be-understood/</guid><description>Nelson Elhage, (Elhage n.d.)
Summary A Growth Mindset oriented approach based on the truth that computer systems are deterministic and can be understood in time that asserts that learning about such systems &amp;ndash; diving into the depths rather than letting systems remain Black boxes &amp;ndash; is worthwhile. Related: Be curious.
Notes At core, computers are built on a set of (mostly) deterministic foundations, which follow strict rules at each tick of the clock.</description></item><item><title>John Salvatier | Reality Has a Surprising Amount of Detail</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/john-salvatier-reality-has-a-surprising-amount-of-detail/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 04:29:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/john-salvatier-reality-has-a-surprising-amount-of-detail/</guid><description>(Salvatier n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes [&amp;hellip;] it&amp;rsquo;s that everything is fiddly, but you only notice the fiddliness when you&amp;rsquo;re new [&amp;hellip;]
The more difficult your mission, the more details there will be that are critical to understand for success.
You might hope that these surprising details are irrelevant to your mission, but not so. Some of them will end up being key.
You might also hope that the important details will be obvious when you run into them, but not so.</description></item><item><title>Ben Kuhn | To Listen Well, Get Curious</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ben-kuhn-to-listen-well-get-curious/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 04:22:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ben-kuhn-to-listen-well-get-curious/</guid><description>Ben Kuhn, (Kuhn n.d.)
Summary Curiosity should underlie a listener&amp;rsquo;s behavior in conversations.
Thoughts Listening well, and asking curious questions, ensures you understand the problem.
I find that my misunderstandings are the result of premature and ill-founded assumptions on my part. There is a balancing act to maintain between reasoning from analogy and reasoning from first principles.
Notes Recently, I realized why people keep giving this weird-seeming advice. Good listeners do often reflect words back—but not because they read it in a book somewhere.</description></item><item><title>Carl R Rogers, Richard E Farson | Active Listening</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/carl-r-rogers-richard-e-farson-active-listening/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 03:46:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/carl-r-rogers-richard-e-farson-active-listening/</guid><description>(Rogers and Farson, n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Rogers, Carl R, and Richard E Farson. n.d. “Active Listening,” 5.</description></item><item><title>Wiktionary | Fait Accompli</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wiktionary-fait-accompli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 09:35:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wiktionary-fait-accompli/</guid><description> Often said of something irreversible and/or performed without going through standard procedure, completed before those affected by it are in a position to query or reverse it.
(“Fait Accompli” 2022)
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Fait Accompli.” 2022. Wiktionary. https://en.wiktionary.org/w/index.php?title=fait_accompli&amp;#38;oldid=65295730.</description></item><item><title>Andy Matuschak | Evergreen Notes Should Be Densely Linked</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/andy-matuschak-evergreen-notes-should-be-densely-linked/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 07:04:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/andy-matuschak-evergreen-notes-should-be-densely-linked/</guid><description>Andy Matuschak, (Matuschak n.d.)
If we push ourselves to add lots of links between our notes, that makes us think expansively about what other concepts might be related to what we&amp;rsquo;re thinking about. It creates pressure to think carefully about how ideas relate to each other (see Understanding requires effortful engagement and Evergreen notes should be concept-oriented). It&amp;rsquo;ll also help you internalize the ideas more deeply through Elaborative encoding.</description></item><item><title>Andy Matuschak | Evergreen Notes</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/andy-matuschak-evergreen-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 17:40:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/andy-matuschak-evergreen-notes/</guid><description>Andy Matuschak, (Matuschak n.d.)
Evergreen notes are written and organized to evolve, contribute, and accumulate over time, across projects. This is an unusual way to think about writing notes: Most people take only transient notes. That&amp;rsquo;s because these practices aren&amp;rsquo;t about writing notes; they&amp;rsquo;re about effectively developing insight: &amp;ldquo;Better note-taking&amp;rdquo; misses the point; what matters is &amp;ldquo;better thinking&amp;rdquo;. When done well, these notes can be quite valuable: Evergreen note-writing as fundamental unit of knowledge work.</description></item><item><title>Tom Limoncelli | What Makes a Sysadmin a Senior Sysadmin?</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tom-limoncelli-what-makes-a-sysadmin-a-senior-sysadmin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 17:12:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tom-limoncelli-what-makes-a-sysadmin-a-senior-sysadmin/</guid><description>Tom Limoncelli, (Limoncelli n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes A senior person demonstrates technical leadership by creating the processes that other people can follow, thereby enabling delegation and multiplying their effectiveness. Maybe the senior person is the only one technical enough to work out the procedure for replacing a bad disk on a server, but they document it in a way that less experience people can do the task. Maybe the senior person is the only one technical enough to set up a massive monitoring system, but they document how to add new devices so that everyone can add to what is monitored.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | Metagaming</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-metagaming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 17:01:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-metagaming/</guid><description>(“Metagaming” 2021)
Metagame, Hypergame, or game about the game, is an approach to a game that transcends or operates outside of the prescribed rules of the game, uses external factors to affect the game, or goes beyond the supposed limits or environment set by the game.
Metagaming might also refer to a game which functions to create or modify the rules of a sub-game. Thus, we might play a metagame selecting which rules will apply during the play of the game itself.</description></item><item><title>Tom Limoncelli | The Right Answer</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tom-limoncelli-the-right-answer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 15:50:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tom-limoncelli-the-right-answer/</guid><description>Tom Limoncelli, (Limoncelli n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes An iMac at work broke and AppleCare gave us the choice of bringing it to one of three places in the local area, or the local AppleStore. Since one of those choices was the CompUSA around the block from us, my co-worker brought it there. And waited. And waited. And was told they were waiting for the part. We called the Apple store who said that they could do most repairs in 24 hours.</description></item><item><title>John Allspaw | On Being A Senior Engineer</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/john-allspaw-on-being-a-senior-engineer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 15:31:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/john-allspaw-on-being-a-senior-engineer/</guid><description>John Allspaw, (Allspaw n.d.)
Summary A list of what John Allspaw sees as qualities of a senior engineer.
Thoughts Notes In order not to confuse titles with expectations that are fuzzy, sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll refer to engineering maturity.
Meaning: I expect a &amp;ldquo;senior&amp;rdquo; engineer to be a mature engineer.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to gloss over the part where one could simply list the technical areas in which a mature engineer should have some level of mastery or understanding (such as &amp;ldquo;Networking&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Filesystems&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Algorithms&amp;rdquo;, etc.</description></item><item><title>Zach Tellman | Trapped in the Technologist Factory</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/zach-tellman-trapped-in-the-technologist-factory/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 09:32:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/zach-tellman-trapped-in-the-technologist-factory/</guid><description>Zach Tellman, (Tellman n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes I learned two lessons from this time in my life. The first was personal: I am, at heart, a technologist. I like to generalize, to abstract. While I believe it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand the context around your software, I&amp;rsquo;m happiest when that context is other people&amp;rsquo;s software.
The second lesson was broader, and less obvious: our industry is designed to foster people like me.</description></item><item><title>Zach Tellman | Senior Engineers Reduce Risk</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/zach-tellman-senior-engineers-reduce-risk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 19:25:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/zach-tellman-senior-engineers-reduce-risk/</guid><description>Zach Tellman, (Tellman n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes Senior engineers reduce risk, in every sense. Often, &amp;ldquo;risk&amp;rdquo; is used to describe technical risk, which is that the software doesn&amp;rsquo;t function properly, or is never completed at all. But there are other issues that can prevent the business atop the software from succeeding - risks around process, or product design, or sales, or the company&amp;rsquo;s culture. A senior engineer understands these risks, and mitigates them where possible.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | And Yet It Moves</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-and-yet-it-moves/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:30:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-and-yet-it-moves/</guid><description>(“And yet It Moves” 2022)
&amp;ldquo;And yet it moves&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Although it does move&amp;rdquo; (Italian: E pur si muove or Eppur si muove) is a phrase attributed to the Italian mathematician, physicist and philosopher Galileo Galilei (1564–1642) in 1633 after being forced to recant his claims that the Earth moves around the Sun, rather than the converse. In this context, the implication of the phrase is: despite his recantation, the Church&amp;rsquo;s proclamations to the contrary, or any other conviction or doctrine of men, the Earth does, in fact, move (around the Sun, and not vice versa).</description></item><item><title>Zach Tellman | Thought Leaders and Chicken Sexers</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/zach-tellman-thought-leaders-and-chicken-sexers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:25:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/zach-tellman-thought-leaders-and-chicken-sexers/</guid><description>Zach Tellman, (Tellman n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes When [tacit] knowledge begins to lead us astray, however, Polanyi tells us we that must delve into it. We must make it explicit. An explicit understanding of speech might be necessary for someone with a speech impediment, but also for a professional performer; to be at the top of your field, it&amp;rsquo;s almost always necessary to transform innate talent into something more.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | Man After Man</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-man-after-man/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 15:08:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-man-after-man/</guid><description>(“Man After Man” 2022)
Summary Thoughts Notes References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Man After Man.” 2022. Wikipedia, February. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Man_After_Man&amp;#38;oldid=1070083811.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | All Tomorrows</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-all-tomorrows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 15:06:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-all-tomorrows/</guid><description>(“All Tomorrows” 2022)
All Tomorrows: A Billion Year Chronicle of the Myriad Species and Mixed Fortunes of Man is a 2006 work of science fiction and speculative evolution written and illustrated by the Turkish artist C. M. Kosemen under the pen name Nemo Ramjet. It explores a hypothetical future path of human evolution set from the near future to a billion years from the present. Several future human species evolve through natural means and through genetic engineering, conducted by both humans themselves and by a mysterious and superior alien species called the Qu.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | Speculative Evolution</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-speculative-evolution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 15:04:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-speculative-evolution/</guid><description>(“Speculative Evolution” 2022)
Speculative evolution is a genre of speculative fiction and an artistic movement focused on hypothetical scenarios in the evolution of life, and a significant form of fictional biology. It is also known as speculative biology and it is referred to as speculative zoology in regards to hypothetical animals. Works incorporating speculative evolution may have entirely conceptual species that evolve on a planet other than Earth, or they may be an alternate history focused on an alternate evolution of terrestrial life.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | Deep Time</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-deep-time/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 13:07:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-deep-time/</guid><description>(“Deep Time” 2021)
Deep time is a term introduced and applied by John McPhee to the concept of geologic time in his Basin and Range, parts of which originally appeared in the New Yorker magazine.
Consider the Earth&amp;rsquo;s history as the old measure of the English yard, the distance from the King&amp;rsquo;s nose to the tip of his outstretched hand. One stroke of a nail file on his middle finger erases human history.</description></item><item><title>Eliezer Yudkowsky | The Fallacy of Gray</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/eliezer-yudkowsky-the-fallacy-of-gray/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 10:30:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/eliezer-yudkowsky-the-fallacy-of-gray/</guid><description>Eliezer Yudkowsky, (Yudkowsky n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes The Sophisticate: &amp;ldquo;The world isn&amp;rsquo;t black and white. No one does pure good or pure bad. It&amp;rsquo;s all gray. Therefore, no one is better than anyone else.&amp;rdquo;
The Zetet: &amp;ldquo;Knowing only gray, you conclude that all grays are the same shade. You mock the simplicity of the two-color view, yet you replace it with a one-color view&amp;rdquo;
—Marc Stiegler, David&amp;rsquo;s Sling
References .</description></item><item><title>The Fallacy of Gray - LessWrong</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the-fallacy-of-gray-lesswrong/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 10:30:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/the-fallacy-of-gray-lesswrong/</guid><description>TODO_AUTHOR, (“The Fallacy of Gray - LessWrong” n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“The Fallacy of Gray - LessWrong.” n.d. Accessed February 17, 2022. https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/dLJv2CoRCgeC2mPgj/the-fallacy-of-gray.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | Serenity Prayer</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-serenity-prayer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 07:20:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-serenity-prayer/</guid><description>Reinhold Niebuhr, (“Serenity Prayer” 2021)
God, grant me the serenity to accept the things I cannot change, courage to change the things I can, and wisdom to know the difference.
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Serenity Prayer.” 2021. Wikipedia, October. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Serenity_Prayer&amp;#38;oldid=1052226839.</description></item><item><title>Marcus Aurelius Antoninus | The Meditations of the Emperor Marcus Antoninus</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/marcus-aurelius-antoninus-the-meditations-of-the-emperor-marcus-antoninus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 06:44:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/marcus-aurelius-antoninus-the-meditations-of-the-emperor-marcus-antoninus/</guid><description>Marcus Aurelius Antoninus, (Antoninus 1944)
Summary Thoughts Notes Title page The Meditations of the Emperor Marcus Antoninus Introduction Book 1 Book 2 2.1 Say to yourself in the early morning: I shall meet to-day inquisitive, ungrateful, violent, treacherous, envious, uncharitable men. All these things have come upon them through ignorance of real good and ill. But I, because I have seen that the nature of good is the right, and of ill the wrong, and that the nature of the man himself who does wrong is akin to my own (not of the same blood and seed, but partaking with me in mind, that is in a portion of divinity), I can neither be harmed by any of them, for no man will involve me in wrong, nor can I be angry with my kinsman or hate him; for we have come into the world to work together, like feet, like hands, like eyelids, like the rows of upper and lower teeth.</description></item><item><title>Five Sentences</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/five-sentences/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 13:21:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/five-sentences/</guid><description> The Problem
E-mail takes too long to respond to, resulting in continuous inbox overflow for those who receive a lot of it.
The Solution
Treat all email responses like SMS text messages, using a set number of letters per response. Since it&amp;rsquo;s too hard to count letters, we count sentences instead.
(“Five Sentences” n.d.)
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Five Sentences.” n.d. Accessed February 15, 2022. http://five.sentenc.es/.</description></item><item><title>ryans01 | No Zero Days</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ryans01-no-zero-days/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 08:33:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/ryans01-no-zero-days/</guid><description>(ryans01 2013)
Summary Thoughts Notes Rule numero uno - There are no more zero days. What&amp;rsquo;s a zero day? A zero day is when you don&amp;rsquo;t do a single fucking thing towards whatever dream or goal or want or whatever that you got going on. No more zeros. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you gotta bust an essay out everyday, that&amp;rsquo;s not the point. The point I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make is that you have to make yourself, promise yourself, that the new SYSTEM you live in is a NON-ZERO system.</description></item><item><title>Andy Matuschak | Knowledge Work Should Accrete</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/andy-matuschak-knowledge-work-should-accrete/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 20:02:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/andy-matuschak-knowledge-work-should-accrete/</guid><description>Andy Matuschak, (Matuschak n.d.)
Many activities in Knowledge work seem to be ephemeral efforts, their outputs mostly discarded after they&amp;rsquo;re completed.
You might wake up to a really tricky email and realize that it connects to something you&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about for a while. You might spend an hour writing a careful reply, capturing your latest thinking. And now&amp;hellip; it lives in your &amp;ldquo;sent&amp;rdquo; folder, and briefly in the impression on your and your colleague&amp;rsquo;s mind.</description></item><item><title>TV Tropes | Xanatos Gambit</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tv-tropes-xanatos-gambit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 08:27:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tv-tropes-xanatos-gambit/</guid><description>(“Xanatos Gambit” n.d.)
A Xanatos Gambit is a plan for which all foreseeable outcomes benefit the creator — including ones that superficially appear to be failure.
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Xanatos Gambit.” n.d. Tv Tropes. Accessed February 9, 2022. https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/XanatosGambit.</description></item><item><title>Adam Zerner | Writing to Think</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/adam-zerner-writing-to-think/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 18:46:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/adam-zerner-writing-to-think/</guid><description>Adam Zerner, (Zerner n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Zerner, Adam. n.d. “Writing to Think.” Accessed February 8, 2022. https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/SKQmvZMTY6zQf3Ktc/writing-to-think.</description></item><item><title>Julian Shapiro | How to Punctuate</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/julian-shapiro-how-to-punctuate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:30:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/julian-shapiro-how-to-punctuate/</guid><description>Julian Shapiro, (Shapiro n.d.)
Incorporate points I agree with into Style Guide Summary Thoughts Notes References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Shapiro, Julian. n.d. “How to Punctuate.” Accessed February 8, 2022. https://www.julian.com/blog/punctuation.</description></item><item><title>Julian Shapiro | Writing Well Handbook</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/julian-shapiro-writing-well-handbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:13:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/julian-shapiro-writing-well-handbook/</guid><description>Julian Shapiro
Notes Introduction Julian Shapiro, (Shapiro n.d.-a)
This handbook helps you write nonfiction books and blogs.
(Shapiro n.d.-a)
What to Write About Julian Shapiro, (Shapiro n.d.-d)
Writing First Drafts Julian Shapiro, (Shapiro n.d.-e)
Rewriting and Editing Julian Shapiro, (Shapiro n.d.-c)
Writing Style Julian Shapiro, (Shapiro n.d.-f)
Practicing Writing Julian Shapiro, (Shapiro n.d.-b)
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Shapiro, Julian. n.d.-a. “The Writing Well Handbook.” Accessed February 8, 2022. https://www.</description></item><item><title>Breck Yunits | Write Thin to Write Fast</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/breck-yunits-write-thin-to-write-fast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 08:20:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/breck-yunits-write-thin-to-write-fast/</guid><description>Breck Yunits, (Yunits n.d.)
Summary Set your editor&amp;rsquo;s column width very low &amp;hellip; 36 characters for me, [your mileage may vary].
Thinner columns help you read faster. Writing speed is dominated by reading speed. If you read faster, you write faster.
Thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve seem content width discussed often when it comes to reading. A width of 72 characters comes to mind, though I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where I picked that up.</description></item><item><title>Tim Peck | What Are the Three Types of Fun?</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tim-peck-what-are-the-three-types-of-fun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 08:09:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/tim-peck-what-are-the-three-types-of-fun/</guid><description>Tim Peck, (Peck 2017)
Summary Type Fun in the moment Fun when looking back 1 Yes Yes 2 No Yes 3 No No Thoughts Notes Type three fun is the sticking point for most people:
[&amp;hellip;] [I]t&amp;rsquo;s the type that makes most of us go crawling back to Type 1, and say, &amp;ldquo;The heck with Type 2, because it&amp;rsquo;s just too damned close to Type 3.</description></item><item><title>Eliezer Yudkowsky | Tsuyoku Naritai! (I Want To Become Stronger)</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/eliezer-yudkowsky-tsuyoku-naritai-i-want-to-become-stronger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 08:06:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/eliezer-yudkowsky-tsuyoku-naritai-i-want-to-become-stronger/</guid><description>Eliezer Yudkowsky, (Yudkowsky 2007)
Summary Thoughts Notes The most important thing is that there should be progress. So long as you keep moving forward you will reach your destination; but if you stop moving you will never reach it.
Tsuyoku naritai is Japanese. Tsuyoku is &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo;; naru is &amp;ldquo;becoming,&amp;rdquo; and the form naritai is &amp;ldquo;want to become.&amp;rdquo; Together it means, &amp;ldquo;I want to become stronger,&amp;rdquo; and it expresses a sentiment embodied more intensely in Japanese works than in any Western literature I&amp;rsquo;ve read.</description></item><item><title>Cedric Chin | To Get Good, Go After The Metagame</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/cedric-chin-to-get-good-go-after-the-metagame/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 08:01:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/cedric-chin-to-get-good-go-after-the-metagame/</guid><description>Cedric Chin, (Chin 2020)
Summary Mastering something requires mastering the literal game as well as the Metagame; in that order.
Thoughts Notes Every sufficiently interesting game has a metagame above it. This is the game about the game. It is often called &amp;lsquo;the meta&amp;rsquo;.
Every sufficiently interesting domain in the world has a meta associated with it.
What is interesting about the meta is that metagames can only be played if you have mastered the basics of the domain.</description></item><item><title>Cedric Chin | The Three Kinds of Non-Fiction Books</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/cedric-chin-the-three-kinds-of-non-fiction-books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:36:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/cedric-chin-the-three-kinds-of-non-fiction-books/</guid><description>Cedric Chin, (Chin 2018)
Summary Thoughts Notes Tree book Narrative book Branch book References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Chin, Cedric. 2018. “The Three Kinds of Non-Fiction Books.” Commonplace - the Commoncog Blog. https://commoncog.com/blog/the-3-kinds-of-non-fiction-book/.</description></item><item><title>Derek Sivers | There's No Speed Limit</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/derek-sivers-theres-no-speed-limit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:34:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/derek-sivers-theres-no-speed-limit/</guid><description>Derek Sivers, (Sivers 2009)
Summary Thoughts Notes Kimo&amp;rsquo;s high expectations set a new pace for me. He taught me that &amp;ldquo;the standard pace is for chumps&amp;rdquo; — that the system is designed so anyone can keep up. If you&amp;rsquo;re more driven than most people, you can do way more than anyone expects. And this principle applies to all of life, not just school.
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Sivers, Derek.</description></item><item><title>Andy Payne | The Myth of the Myth of the 10x Programmer</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/andy-payne-the-myth-of-the-myth-of-the-10x-programmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:33:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/andy-payne-the-myth-of-the-myth-of-the-10x-programmer/</guid><description>Andy Payne, (Payne 2020)
Summary Thoughts This reminds me of a way of conceptualizing a &amp;ldquo;10x&amp;rdquo; programmer (though I no longer recall where I read the idea): 10x programmers are not 10x because they code/write/etc 10x faster; they&amp;rsquo;re 10x because they solve the big problems that a non-10x programmer cannot solve.
Notes I don&amp;rsquo;t know anyone 10x faster than their peers in solving well-defined programming problems.
&amp;hellip;
[H]ighly productive developers (10x or otherwise) are problem-solving at a much higher level.</description></item><item><title>James Altucher | The Ultimate Guide for Becoming an Idea Machine</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/james-altucher-the-ultimate-guide-for-becoming-an-idea-machine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:16:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/james-altucher-the-ultimate-guide-for-becoming-an-idea-machine/</guid><description>James Altucher, (Altucher 2014)
Summary Thoughts Notes If I say, &amp;ldquo;write down ten ideas for books you can write&amp;rdquo; I bet you can easily write down four or five. I can write down four or five right now. But at six it starts to get hard. &amp;ldquo;Hmmm,&amp;rdquo; you think, &amp;ldquo;what else can I come up with?&amp;rdquo;
This is when the brain is sweating.
Note that when you exercise in the gym, your muscles don&amp;rsquo;t start to build until you break a sweat.</description></item><item><title>Walter Lippmann | The Basic Problem of Democracy</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/walter-lippmann-the-basic-problem-of-democracy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:13:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/walter-lippmann-the-basic-problem-of-democracy/</guid><description>Walter Lippman, (Lippmann 1919)
Summary A well written essay whose thesis, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit embarrassed to say, eludes me.
Thoughts I expect one could find gold in this essay but I think I will instead read, as one commenter recommended, &amp;ldquo;Goliath&amp;rdquo; by Matt Stoller.
Notes If we substitute the word indifference for the word liberty, we shall come much closer to the real intention that lies behind the classic argument.</description></item><item><title>Scott Alexander | Socratic Grilling</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-socratic-grilling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:03:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-socratic-grilling/</guid><description>Scott Alexander, (Alexander 2020)
Summary Socratic grilling is &amp;ldquo;like Socratic questioning, but a little harsher and more confrontational in order to get to the point more quickly&amp;rdquo; (Alexander 2020). Scott Alexander encourages leaning in to such conversations without shutting them down with an &amp;ldquo;I know more than you do&amp;rdquo;- or &amp;ldquo;Just because&amp;rdquo;-type responses.
Thoughts The learning done through Socratic questioning is worth the potential friction of such a conversation. Care should be taken, before engaging in such conversation, to be sure the other participant(s) aren&amp;rsquo;t doing Ian Danskin | Control the Conversation.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | SMART Criteria</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-smart-criteria/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:59:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-smart-criteria/</guid><description>(“SMART Criteria” 2022)
SMART goals are:
Specific – target a specific area Measurable – quantify or at least suggest an indicator of progress Assignable – specify who will do it Realistic – state what results can realistically be achieved, given available resources Time-related – specify when the result(s) can be achieved References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“SMART Criteria.” 2022. Wikipedia, January. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=SMART_criteria&amp;#38;oldid=1067426737.</description></item><item><title>Michael W. Donnino et al. | Psychophysiologic Symptom Relief Therapy for Chronic Back Pain: A Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/michael-w.-donnino-et-al.-psychophysiologic-symptom-relief-therapy-for-chronic-back-pain-a-pilot-randomized-controlled-trial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:48:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/michael-w.-donnino-et-al.-psychophysiologic-symptom-relief-therapy-for-chronic-back-pain-a-pilot-randomized-controlled-trial/</guid><description>(Donnino et al. 2021)
Summary Thoughts Notes PSRT is a treatment program designed for patients with non-specific chronic back pain. The intervention consists of a one-on-one interview with the investigator, group educational and skills-training sessions over a four-week period for approximately 1.5-2 hours per session twice per week, followed by an eight-week mindfulness-based stress reduction program plus one full- day session/retreat. The course is delivered in small groups facilitated by a trained instructor.</description></item><item><title>Sam Altman | Productivity</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/sam-altman-productivity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:46:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/sam-altman-productivity/</guid><description>Sam Altman, (Altman 2018)
Summary Thoughts Notes It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how fast you move if it&amp;rsquo;s in a worthless direction. Picking the right thing to work on is the most important element of productivity and usually almost ignored.
The most impressive people I know have strong beliefs about the world, which is rare in the general population. If you find yourself always agreeing with whomever you last spoke with, that&amp;rsquo;s bad.</description></item><item><title>Valentine | Noticing the Taste of Lotus</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/valentine-noticing-the-taste-of-lotus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:33:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/valentine-noticing-the-taste-of-lotus/</guid><description>Michael Smith, (Valentine 2018)
Duncan Sabien sometimes talks about &amp;ldquo;lotus-eating&amp;rdquo;. He&amp;rsquo;s referring to a part of the Odyssey where they land on an island of &amp;ldquo;lotus-eaters&amp;rdquo;. It turns out that once you eat some of this kind of lotus, all you want to do is eat more. You stop caring about your other goals. The lotus just grabs your wants directly.
The idea of noticing the taste of lotus is closely related to mindfulness and attention.</description></item><item><title>Alexey Nikitin | My least favorite Git commit</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/alexey-nikitin-my-least-favorite-git-commit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:31:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/alexey-nikitin-my-least-favorite-git-commit/</guid><description>Alexey Nikitin, (Nikitin 2019)
Summary Thoughts See: Documenting Your Work
Notes The essay isn&amp;rsquo;t written in English. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Google Translate to read and quote.
Commit messages do not help to find problems and their causes
[&amp;hellip;] very often I cannot find the commit in which the change I need was made. First, on a line that works erroneously, there are usually several commits, and you need to look at everything.</description></item><item><title>David Thompson | My Favourite Git Commit</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/david-thompson-my-favourite-git-commit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:26:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/david-thompson-my-favourite-git-commit/</guid><description>David Thompson, (Thompson 2019)
Summary Thoughts See: Documenting Your Work
Notes Dan Carley&amp;rsquo;s commit in alphagov/govuk-puppet:
Convert template to US-ASCII to fix error I introduced some tests in a feature branch to match the contents of `/etc/nginx/router_routes.conf`. They worked fine when run with `bundle exec rake spec` or `bundle exec rspec modules/router/spec`. But when run as `bundle exec rake` each should block failed with: ArgumentError: invalid byte sequence in US-ASCII I eventually found that removing the `.</description></item><item><title>moridinamael | The Monthly Newsletter as Thinking Tool</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/moridinamael-the-monthly-newsletter-as-thinking-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:19:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/moridinamael-the-monthly-newsletter-as-thinking-tool/</guid><description>Matt Freeman, (moridinamael 2018)
Summary Thoughts Notes The easiest, very high ROI step is to simply open up a new Evernote document on the first of each month and title it &amp;ldquo;February 2018 Update&amp;rdquo; or whatever. Then just try to keep that tab open. You&amp;rsquo;ll find stuff to put in there. What I end up writing generally falls into a small number of categories:
Links to things that I think my friend would be interested in, with a bit of discussion of why I think it&amp;rsquo;s interesting.</description></item><item><title>Elizabeth J. Marsh, Andrew C. Butler | Memory in Educational Settings</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/elizabeth-j.-marsh-andrew-c.-butler-memory-in-educational-settings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 21:10:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/elizabeth-j.-marsh-andrew-c.-butler-memory-in-educational-settings/</guid><description>TODO_AUTHOR, (Marsh and Butler 2013)
Summary Retrieval or re-experiencing a memory will increase retention. Studying should be somewhat difficult; neither too difficult that the subject is unable to overcome the challenge, nor too easy. The difficulty is desirable feature of the process of studying in that the difficulty improves retention. One does not need to be aware of the specific benefits of a study method to benefit from them.</description></item><item><title>Neel Nanda | Meaningful Rest</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/neel-nanda-meaningful-rest/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 20:52:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/neel-nanda-meaningful-rest/</guid><description>Neel Nanda, (Nanda n.d.)
Create concept post for the idea of engaging in meaningful rest Summary Thoughts Notes An exercise: Set a 5 minute timer, and list the things you want to do when you feel tired and low-energy. Then, set another 5 minute timer, and list the things you feel rejuvenated after having done - the things you like doing when low-energy.
If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, these lists are basically disjoint!</description></item><item><title>Kamran Ahmed | Levels of Seniority</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/kamran-ahmed-levels-of-seniority/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 20:50:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/kamran-ahmed-levels-of-seniority/</guid><description>Kamran Ahmed, (Ahmed n.d.)
Summary The most important traits that you need to have in order to step up in your career are: not settling with mediocrity, having an open mindset, being humble, learning from your mistakes, working on the challenging problems and having an opportunity mindset rather than a complaining one.
Thoughts Notes I have seen fresh graduates having no industry experience get up to speed quickly and producing work of a Senior Engineer and I have seen Senior developers labeled &amp;ldquo;senior&amp;rdquo; merely because of their age and &amp;ldquo;years of experience&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Stephen Kuenzli | Key Practices for Achieving Large Professional Goals</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/stephen-kuenzli-key-practices-for-achieving-large-professional-goals/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 20:49:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/stephen-kuenzli-key-practices-for-achieving-large-professional-goals/</guid><description>Stephen Kuenzli, (Kuenzli 2019)
Summary I attribute much of my success in 2019 to the practices of:
writing to develop my thoughts learning to focus I wrote a lot in 2019 &amp;hellip; This practice of writing resulted in a couple major changes:
I now use writing as a primary mechanism to develop my thoughts on a subject Writing is now a healthy habit for my professional skills and business Kuenzli mentions that they &amp;ldquo;really learned how to focus and extract much more value out of the time I have available&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Anna Salamon | Humans Are Not Automatically Strategic</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/anna-salamon-humans-are-not-automatically-strategic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 20:45:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/anna-salamon-humans-are-not-automatically-strategic/</guid><description>Anna Salamon, (Salamon 2010)
Summary Thoughts Notes Why will a randomly chosen eight-year-old fail a calculus test? Because most possible answers are wrong, and there is no force to guide him to the correct answers. (There is no need to postulate a &amp;ldquo;fear of success&amp;rdquo;; most ways writing or not writing on a calculus test constitute failure, and so people, and rocks, fail calculus tests by default.)
Why do most of us, most of the time, choose to &amp;ldquo;pursue our goals&amp;rdquo; through routes that are far less effective than the routes we could find if we tried?</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | Zettelkasten</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-zettelkasten/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 18:03:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-zettelkasten/</guid><description>(“Zettelkasten” 2021)
A zettelkasten is a personal knowledge management system consisting of densely interlinked (usually) short notes. The system was originally implemented with index cards. Nowadays there are digital solutions.
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Zettelkasten.” 2021. Wikipedia, December. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Zettelkasten&amp;#38;oldid=1060558761.</description></item><item><title>S Keshav | How to Read a Paper</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/s-keshav-how-to-read-a-paper/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/s-keshav-how-to-read-a-paper/</guid><description>(Keshav, n.d.)
Notes References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}Keshav, S. n.d. “How to Read a Paper.”</description></item><item><title>Jason Fried | Habits Always Form</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/jason-fried-habits-always-form/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:53:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/jason-fried-habits-always-form/</guid><description>Jason Fried, (Fried 2019)
Habits are always forming. No matter what you do, you&amp;rsquo;re also forming habits too. Keep that in mind with whatever you do.
When we talk about habits, we generally talk about learning good habits. Or forming good habits. Both of these outcomes suggest we can end up with the habits we want. And technically we can! But most of the habits we have are habits we ended up with after years of unconscious behavior.</description></item><item><title>Anna Salamon | Learned Blankness</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/anna-salamon-learned-blankness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:49:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/anna-salamon-learned-blankness/</guid><description>Anna Salamon, (Salamon 2011)
Summary Thoughts Notes Martin Seligman coined the term &amp;ldquo;learned helplessness&amp;rdquo; to describe a condition in which someone has learned to behave as though they were helpless. I think we need a term for learned helplessness about thinking (in a particular domain). I&amp;rsquo;ll call this &amp;ldquo;learned blankness&amp;rdquo;. Folks who fall prey to learned blankness may still take actions &amp;ndash; sometimes my students practiced the procedures again and again, hired a tutor, etc.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | Law of Triviality</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-law-of-triviality/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:47:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-law-of-triviality/</guid><description>(“Law of Triviality” 2021)
[&amp;hellip;] people [&amp;hellip;] typically give disproportionate weight to trivial issues.
Also known as &amp;ldquo;bike-shedding&amp;rdquo;.
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Law of Triviality.” 2021. Wikipedia, December. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Law_of_triviality&amp;#38;oldid=1058709714.</description></item><item><title>Paul Graham | How to Write Usefully</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/paul-graham-how-to-write-usefully/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:42:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/paul-graham-how-to-write-usefully/</guid><description>Paul Graham, (Graham n.d.)
Summary A useful essay is one which is novel, correct, important, and strong:
A novel essay communicates a &amp;ldquo;new thing&amp;rdquo; (point of view, fact, opinion, etc) to at least some of its audience. A correct essay is factually accurate; insofar as is possible. An important essay matters to at least some people. You can measure it by the product of the number of people for which your points matter and how much it matters to those people.</description></item><item><title>Scott Alexander | For, Then Against, High-Saturated-Fat Diets</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-for-then-against-high-saturated-fat-diets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:33:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-for-then-against-high-saturated-fat-diets/</guid><description>Scott Alexander, (Alexander 2020)
Summary Discussion, without firm conclusion, regarding the source of the American obesity epidemic.
Thoughts Perfectionism A sentence in the beginning of the essay stood out to me:
I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that another blog called Hyperlipid has a deeper investigation, but I&amp;rsquo;ve only scratched the surface of them. [&amp;hellip;] I don&amp;rsquo;t claim to fully understand these people and I apologize for any misrepresentations I might be making.</description></item><item><title>Cedric Chin | Expertise Is 'Just' Pattern Matching</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/cedric-chin-expertise-is-just-pattern-matching/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 16:53:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/cedric-chin-expertise-is-just-pattern-matching/</guid><description>Cedric Chin, (Chin 2020)
Summary Expertise is just pattern matching. In other words, being an expert at something is equivalent to being really good at (1) recognizing situations and (2) knowing how to respond to those situations. Simple, right?
Notes [&amp;hellip;] the notion that &amp;lsquo;expertise is simply pattern-matching&amp;rsquo; [&amp;hellip;] follows naturally from two other ideas that I&amp;rsquo;ve covered extensively on Commonplace over the past year.
The first idea is the &amp;lsquo;recognition-primed decision making&amp;rsquo; model developed by psychologist Gary Klein and his collaborators, working in the US military and with expert firefighters and NICU nurses.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | Festina Lente</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-festina-lente/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 16:50:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-festina-lente/</guid><description> [&amp;hellip;] a classical adage and oxymoron meaning &amp;ldquo;make haste slowly&amp;rdquo; (sometimes rendered in English as &amp;ldquo;more haste, less speed&amp;rdquo;).
(“Festina Lente” 2022)
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Festina Lente.” 2022. Wikipedia, February. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Festina_lente&amp;#38;oldid=1070080472.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia | Dunning-Kruger Effect</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-dunning-kruger-effect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 16:07:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/wikipedia-dunning-kruger-effect/</guid><description>(“DunningKruger Effect” 2022)
[T]he cognitive bias whereby people with low ability at a task overestimate their ability. Some researchers also include in their definition the opposite effect for high performers: their tendency to underestimate their skills.
References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“DunningKruger Effect.” 2022. Wikipedia, February. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect&amp;#38;oldid=1070028100.</description></item><item><title> Dan Moore | Cultivate the Skill of Undivided Attention, or "Deep Work"</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/dan-moore-cultivate-the-skill-of-undivided-attention-or-deep-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/dan-moore-cultivate-the-skill-of-undivided-attention-or-deep-work/</guid><description>Dan Moore, (Moores 2019)
Summary Thoughts Notes Here&amp;rsquo;s the list of topics that I&amp;rsquo;d need to dedicate significant time to, in order to close the gap between me and the senior developers on our team, that I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered in my last two days of work:
Breaking complex unknowns into simpler unknowns that can be further split into individual tickets Adding tests to complex, legacy code, to guide further refactoring of said code.</description></item><item><title>Cedric Chin | What Is a Career Moat?</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/cedric-chin-what-is-a-career-moat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 15:53:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/cedric-chin-what-is-a-career-moat/</guid><description>Cedric Chin, (Chin 2018)
Summary Thoughts Notes A career moat is an individual&amp;rsquo;s ability to maintain competitive advantages over your competition (say, in the job market) in order to protect your long term prospects, your employability, and your ability to generate sufficient financial returns to support the life you want to live. Just like a medieval castle, the moat serves to protect those inside the fortress and their riches from outsiders.</description></item><item><title>James Stuber | Master Boring Fundamentals 01: Boring Is Fun</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/james-stuber-master-boring-fundamentals-01-boring-is-fun/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 15:51:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/james-stuber-master-boring-fundamentals-01-boring-is-fun/</guid><description>James Stuber, (Stuber n.d.)
Summary Thoughts Notes We go to incredible lengths to avoid actions that we know are good for us.
Ski enthusiast Tim Peck shows us that there are actually two types of fun:
Type 1 Fun: Pure fun, untarnished by setbacks Type 2 Fun: Suffering now; fun after the fact, in retrospect Not Fun: Not fun now, not fun later, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m never doing that again&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Scott Alexander | Book Review: The Seven Principles For Making Marriage Work</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-book-review-the-seven-principles-for-making-marriage-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 15:43:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/scott-alexander-book-review-the-seven-principles-for-making-marriage-work/</guid><description>Scott Alexander, (Alexander 2020) , The Seven Principles for Making Marriage Work
Summary The legend of John Gottman&amp;rsquo;s marriage counselling success isn&amp;rsquo;t supported by the underlying research at a statistical level; however, the techniques he advocates may help anyway.
Thoughts I enjoyed the personality that this essay had. A more direct essay could have started out by stating the problems with Gottman&amp;rsquo;s research. You could argue this essay buried the lede.</description></item><item><title>Milan Griffes | (A)</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/milan-griffes-a/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 13:12:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/milan-griffes-a/</guid><description>Milan Griffes, (Griffes n.d.)
Summary Dead links are inevitable if your written content lives long enough online. Include archive links alongside links to off-domain content &amp;ldquo;(a)&amp;rdquo;.
Thoughts I like the idea of including an archive link when linking to off-domain content. It seems like something that I could automate through some &amp;ldquo;presubmit&amp;rdquo; step of the publishing process. I&amp;rsquo;ve looked around but haven&amp;rsquo;t found an addon/extension for any of the popular blogging solutions which provides an easy way to include such links.</description></item><item><title>Leading Indicator</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/leading-indicator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 08:18:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/leading-indicator/</guid><description> Leading indicators are indicators that usually, but not always, change before the [a thing] as a whole changes. They are therefore useful as short-term predictors of the [a thing].
(“Economic Indicator” 2021)
Examples Amount of sleep someone gets as a leading indicator for their focus during the day. References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Economic Indicator.” 2021. Wikipedia, December. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Economic_indicator&amp;#38;oldid=1062025570.</description></item><item><title>Lagging Indicator</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/lagging-indicator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 08:07:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/lagging-indicator/</guid><description> Lagging indicators are indicators that usually change after [a thing] as a whole does. [&amp;hellip;] The unemployment rate is a lagging indicator: employment tends to increase two or three quarters after an upturn in [a thing].
(“Economic Indicator” 2021)
Examples References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“Economic Indicator.” 2021. Wikipedia, December. https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Economic_indicator&amp;#38;oldid=1062025570.</description></item><item><title>Three Components of Emotion</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/three-components-of-emotion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 01:03:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/three-components-of-emotion/</guid><description>(“The Science of Emotion: Exploring the Basics of Emotional Psychology” 2019)
A subjective experience. A physiological response. A behavioral, or expressive, response. References .csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}“The Science of Emotion: Exploring the Basics of Emotional Psychology.” 2019. Uwa Online. https://online.uwa.edu/news/emotional-psychology/.</description></item></channel></rss>