<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>writing on Cash Weaver</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/categories/writing/</link><description>Recent content in writing on Cash Weaver</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 11:26:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cashweaver.com/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use Plain Language</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/use_plain_language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 11:26:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/use_plain_language/</guid><description> Plain language makes it easier [&amp;hellip;] to read, understand, and use [writing].
plainlanguage.gov
Quotes The Shorter and Plainer the Better Use The Smallest Word That Does The Job If I Had More Time, I Would Have Written A Shorter Letter</description></item><item><title>Write Prolifically; Write Succinctly</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/write_prolifically_write_succinctly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 07:28:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/write_prolifically_write_succinctly/</guid><description>Summary Notes That is: write more things, but have each thing be shorter. This has a few key benefits.
First, it lowers the barrier for writing something. Instead of worrying about whether you can write enough about whatever it is you want to write about, just write, and don&amp;rsquo;t worry if it turns out short.
Second, it makes reading things easier. People are busy, and generally don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of time to spend on any one thing.</description></item><item><title>How to Write Usefully</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/how_to_write_usefully/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 17:46:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/how_to_write_usefully/</guid><description>Summary A useful essay is one which is novel, correct, important, and strong:
A novel essay communicates a &amp;ldquo;new thing&amp;rdquo; (point of view, fact, opinion, etc) to at least some of its audience. A correct essay is factually accurate; insofar as is possible. An important essay matters to at least some people. You can measure it by the product of the number of people for which your points matter and how much it matters to those people.</description></item><item><title>Write thin to write fast</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/write_thin_to_write_fast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 21:52:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/write_thin_to_write_fast/</guid><description>Summary Set your editor&amp;rsquo;s column width very low &amp;hellip; 36 characters for me, [your mileage may vary].
Thinner columns help you read faster. Writing speed is dominated by reading speed. If you read faster, you write faster.
Thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve seem content width discussed often when it comes to reading. A width of 72 characters comes to mind, though I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where I picked that up.</description></item><item><title>Monthly Newsletter as a Thinking Tool</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/monthly_newsletter_as_a_thinking_tool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:48:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/monthly_newsletter_as_a_thinking_tool/</guid><description>The easiest, very high ROI step is to simply open up a new Evernote document on the first of each month and title it &amp;ldquo;February 2018 Update&amp;rdquo; or whatever. Then just try to keep that tab open. You&amp;rsquo;ll find stuff to put in there. What I end up writing generally falls into a small number of categories:
Links to things that I think my friend would be interested in, with a bit of discussion of why I think it&amp;rsquo;s interesting.</description></item></channel></rss>