<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>recipe on Cash Prokop-Weaver</title><link>http://notes.cashpw.com/tags/recipe/</link><description>Recent content in recipe on Cash Prokop-Weaver</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 08:21:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://notes.cashpw.com/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creamy vegan mushroom lasagna</title><link>http://notes.cashpw.com/posts/0905eaa4-16e9-4abb-b78c-0b00f855e60d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 08:21:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://notes.cashpw.com/posts/0905eaa4-16e9-4abb-b78c-0b00f855e60d/</guid><description>This recipe is from (Murnane 2017) and (Murnane n.d.).
Ingredients Olive, grape seed, or coconut oil, or veggie broth for sautéing 3 garlic cloves, minced 16 ounces mushrooms, chopped (you can use a mix of different mushrooms) 1 tablespoon tamari or coconut aminos 1 teaspoon dried thyme 3/4 cup raw cashews, soaked for a few hours (overnight is best), drained 1 cup veggie broth 2 big handfuls spinach 10 ounces gluten-free lasagna noodles 4 cups marinara sauce, store-bought or homemade Nutritional yeast (optional) Steps Preheat the oven to 350ºF.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This recipe is from (<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_1">Murnane 2017</a>) and (<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_2">Murnane n.d.</a>).</p>
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<div class="ingredients">
<ul>
<li>Olive, grape seed, or coconut oil, or veggie broth for sautéing</li>
<li>3 garlic cloves, minced</li>
<li>16 ounces mushrooms, chopped (you can use a mix of different mushrooms)</li>
<li>1 tablespoon tamari or coconut aminos</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dried thyme</li>
<li>3/4 cup raw cashews, <strong>soaked for a few hours (overnight is best)</strong>, drained</li>
<li>1 cup veggie broth</li>
<li>2 big handfuls spinach</li>
<li>10 ounces gluten-free lasagna noodles</li>
<li>4 cups marinara sauce, store-bought or homemade</li>
<li>Nutritional yeast (optional)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h2 id="steps">Steps</h2>
<ol>
<li>Preheat the oven to 350ºF.</li>
<li>In a large skillet, heat a glug of oil or veggie broth over medium. When the pan is hot, add the garlic and sauté until it becomes fragrant. This will take about a minute. Add the mushrooms, tamari, and thyme. Cook, stirring every minute or so, for 6 to 8 minutes or until the mushrooms release their water and a little broth starts to form.</li>
<li>Combine the cashews and veggie broth in a high-speed blender and blend until the mixture is completely smooth. This might take up to 5 minutes, depending on the speed and power of your blender. Pour the cashew sauce into the pan with the mushrooms. Reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer for a couple minutes to let the sauce thicken, stirring frequently. Throw in the spinach and stir for another minute.</li>
<li>Prepare the lasagna noodles according to the package instructions. Make sure to do this after your mushroom sauce is ready to go, so the noodles don&rsquo;t sit for too long and start sticking together.</li>
<li>Spread a third of the marinara sauce on the bottom of an 8-by-11-inch baking dish. Add a layer of noodles. Cover the noodles with half of the mushroom cream. Add a layer of noodles. Use another third of the marinara to cover these noodles. Add the remaining mushroom cream. Add the last layer of noodles and cover it with the remaining marinara sauce.</li>
<li>Cover the lasagna with aluminum foil and bake for 30 minutes. Remove the foil, add a sprinkle of nutritional yeast over the top, if you like, and bake for another 15 minutes. Let the lasagna rest for 5 minutes before serving.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="flashcards">Flashcards</h2>
<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<style>.csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}</style><div class="csl-bib-body">
  <div class="csl-entry"><a id="citeproc_bib_item_1"></a>Murnane, Jessica. 2017. <i>One Part Plant: A Simple Guide to Eating Real, One Meal at a Time</i>. First edition. New York, NY: Harper Wave, an imprint of HarperCollinsPublishers.</div>
  <div class="csl-entry"><a id="citeproc_bib_item_2"></a>———. n.d. “Creamy Vegan Mushroom Lasagna.” <i>Epicurious</i>. Accessed October 31, 2022. <a href="https://www.epicurious.com/recipes/food/views/creamy-mushroom-lasagna">https://www.epicurious.com/recipes/food/views/creamy-mushroom-lasagna</a>.</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Wash the flour seitan</title><link>http://notes.cashpw.com/posts/aec8ffce-c854-4800-8a3d-bf8ac3616eef/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 19:45:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://notes.cashpw.com/posts/aec8ffce-c854-4800-8a3d-bf8ac3616eef/</guid><description>Wash the flour method is a way to make Seitan from high-gluten flour.
3 parts high-gluten flour (&amp;gt;= 11% protein content) 1 part water (may need to be higher depending on the flour you use) Combine ingredients
(Seitan Society n.d.)
Place the ball of dough in a bowl and cover it with cool water for at least 1 hour, but not longer than 8-10.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wash the flour method is a way to make <a href="/posts/2caa9715-d216-41c4-babb-c6e66364ac6d/">Seitan</a> from high-gluten flour.</p>
<div class="ingredients">
<ul>
<li>3 parts high-gluten flour (&gt;= 11% protein content)</li>
<li>1 part water (may need to be higher depending on the flour you use)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Combine ingredients</p>
<blockquote>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="/ox-hugo/2022-09-27_19-53-58_washed-step1-800-200x200.jpg"/> 
</figure>

<p>(<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_2">Seitan Society n.d.</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<p>Place the ball of dough in a bowl and cover it with cool water for at least 1 hour, but not longer than 8-10.</p>
<blockquote>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="/ox-hugo/2022-09-27_19-57-32_washed-step2-800-200x200.jpg"/> 
</figure>

<p>(<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_2">Seitan Society n.d.</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<p>Start washing!</p>
<blockquote>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="/ox-hugo/2022-09-27_19-59-09_washed-step3-800-200x200.jpg"/> 
</figure>

<p>At this point move the bowl to the sink and grab a colander. Discard the water covering the dough and fill the bowl again with cool, clean water. As the new water fills the bowl, begin stretching and kneading the dough. Keeping your hands and dough in the bowl of water, continue kneading and stretching until the water becomes very opaque.</p>
<p>(<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_2">Seitan Society n.d.</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<p>Dump out your milky water, using a colander to catch the dough ball and any stray pieces</p>
<blockquote>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="/ox-hugo/2022-09-27_20-00-03_washed-step4-800-200x200.jpg"/> 
</figure>

<p>Cover your dough ball again, this time using luke-warm water, and continue to stretch and knead until the water becomes opaque again. Alternating cool and warm water affects how the dough breaks apart and comes back together again. The goal of this is to hopefully lessen the amount of times you need to wash. However, you can do all cool water and get the same result. It is not recommended to use water that is too warm or hot, because your dough can become stickier or more gluey and harder to work with.</p>
<p>(<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_2">Seitan Society n.d.</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<p>Repeat steps 3 and 4</p>
<blockquote>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="/ox-hugo/2022-09-27_20-20-14_washed-flour-seitan-stages-min-1.jpg"/> 
</figure>

<p>(<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_1">Le 2021</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
<!--quoteend-->
<blockquote>
<p>You will likely need to repeat this process at least few times. You will see the dough begin to look more stringy and feel a little &ldquo;squeaky&rdquo; between your fingers. The more starch you wash out, the more chewy your seitan will become, so the end result is up to you.</p>
<p>[&hellip;]</p>
<p>Wash until the water is at least a little bit cloudy.</p>
<p>(<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_2">Seitan Society n.d.</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<p>Once you have finished washing to your desired level of water clarity, let the dough rest in the colander for at least 20 minutes</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This is to both drain the excess water and let the strands begin to develop. If you are adding additional spices or proteins, proceed to step [7]. If you are not, you should let it rest even longer until the gluten becomes very elastic and you are able to stretch it far without it breaking.</p>
<p>(<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_2">Seitan Society n.d.</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<p>(optional) Add in seasonings</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A good rule of thumb if adding proteins or liquids is to only add about 2oz to this size dough ball so your seitan does not become too soft. I prefer just adding in dry spices to keep the texture chewier, but you can also add liquids such as soy sauce or liquid smoke to boost flavor, and/or additional proteins such as tofu or beans to soften the texture of your final result and also make your seitan a complete protein. My preferred method for incorporating them is to use a food processor, but you can also cut them into the dough or knead them in by hand. Then you will need to let the dough rest again until it starts to come back together and become more elastic and stretchy. You want it strong enough to knot, even if you do not intend to cook it that way. This usually takes about 20 minutes, but can take up to an hour or so depending on what you&rsquo;ve added. You can also leave it sit overnight so the gluten continues to develop, but that is unnecessary.</p>
<p>(<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_2">Seitan Society n.d.</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<p>Prepare <a href="/posts/2caa9715-d216-41c4-babb-c6e66364ac6d/">Seitan</a> for cooking</p>
<p>Stretch and knot (braid) the <a href="/posts/2caa9715-d216-41c4-babb-c6e66364ac6d/">Seitan</a> dough.</p>
<blockquote>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="/ox-hugo/2022-09-27_20-06-44_braided-washed-flour-seitan-min-1.jpg"/> 
</figure>

<p>(<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_1">Le 2021</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<p>Cook <a href="/posts/2caa9715-d216-41c4-babb-c6e66364ac6d/">Seitan</a></p>
<p>Bring enough broth to cover <a href="/posts/2caa9715-d216-41c4-babb-c6e66364ac6d/">Seitan</a> to a simmer in a pot, then add the <a href="/posts/2caa9715-d216-41c4-babb-c6e66364ac6d/">Seitan</a> and cook for 2+ hours (depending on the thickness of the dough).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Let it rest in the fridge for at least 8 hours</p>
<blockquote>
<p>While you can skip this step, the texture will not have had a chance to completely firm up.</p>
<p>(<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_2">Seitan Society n.d.</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="flashcards">Flashcards</h2>
<h3 id="describe-the-steps-to-make-wash-the-flour-seitan--wash-the-flour-seitan-dot-md">Describe the steps to make <a href="/posts/aec8ffce-c854-4800-8a3d-bf8ac3616eef/">Wash the flour seitan</a></h3>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>position</th>
<th>ease</th>
<th>box</th>
<th>interval</th>
<th>due</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>front</td>
<td>2.05</td>
<td>7</td>
<td>172.74</td>
<td>2023-10-20T12:35:20Z</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<ol>
<li>Combine flour and water</li>
<li>Cover dough ball with water and let rest for \(1&lt;x&lt;8\) hours</li>
<li>Wash flour repeatedly until you achieve desired water clarity</li>
<li>Add seasonings</li>
<li>Let rest for \(&gt;1\) hour(s)</li>
<li>Braid the dough</li>
<li>Simmer dough in broth</li>
<li>Let dough rest for \(&gt;8\) hours</li>
</ol>
<h4 id="source">Source</h4>
<p><a href="/posts/aec8ffce-c854-4800-8a3d-bf8ac3616eef/">Wash the flour method</a></p>
<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<style>.csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}</style><div class="csl-bib-body">
  <div class="csl-entry"><a id="citeproc_bib_item_1"></a>Le, Lisa. 2021. “Washed Flour Seitan Method.” <i>The Viet Vegan</i>. <a href="https://thevietvegan.com/washed-flour-seitan-method/">https://thevietvegan.com/washed-flour-seitan-method/</a>.</div>
  <div class="csl-entry"><a id="citeproc_bib_item_2"></a>Seitan Society. n.d. “‘Wash the Flour’ Method.” <i>Seitan Society</i>. Accessed September 2, 2022. <a href="https://seitansociety.com/wash-the-flour-method/">https://seitansociety.com/wash-the-flour-method/</a>.</div>
</div>
<h2 id="backlinks">Backlinks</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="/posts/2caa9715-d216-41c4-babb-c6e66364ac6d/">Seitan</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Better than bullion: Seasoned vegetable base</title><link>http://notes.cashpw.com/posts/94acace5-6bbb-44ee-9cb9-fef318283d57/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 14:18:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://notes.cashpw.com/posts/94acace5-6bbb-44ee-9cb9-fef318283d57/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 teaspoon Better than bullion: Seasoned vegetable base 1 cup water Flashcards Backlinks Vegetable broth</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<div class="ingredients">
<ul>
<li>1 teaspoon Better than bullion: Seasoned vegetable base</li>
<li>1 cup water</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h2 id="flashcards">Flashcards</h2>
<h2 id="backlinks">Backlinks</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="/posts/b3c5a8d6-11f0-4882-8bd1-dc4a09eca8c5/">Vegetable broth</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Vegetable broth</title><link>http://notes.cashpw.com/posts/b3c5a8d6-11f0-4882-8bd1-dc4a09eca8c5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 11:36:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://notes.cashpw.com/posts/b3c5a8d6-11f0-4882-8bd1-dc4a09eca8c5/</guid><description>Quick Better than bullion: Seasoned vegetable base From scratch Flashcards Backlinks Cayla&amp;rsquo;s quarantine ramen</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="quick">Quick</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="/posts/94acace5-6bbb-44ee-9cb9-fef318283d57/">Better than bullion: Seasoned vegetable base</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="from-scratch">From scratch</h2>
<h2 id="flashcards">Flashcards</h2>
<h2 id="backlinks">Backlinks</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="/posts/9b56dca0-39e0-4dec-a269-dd7773257c2b/">Cayla&rsquo;s quarantine ramen</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Cayla's quarantine ramen</title><link>http://notes.cashpw.com/posts/9b56dca0-39e0-4dec-a269-dd7773257c2b/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://notes.cashpw.com/posts/9b56dca0-39e0-4dec-a269-dd7773257c2b/</guid><description>Ingredients Broth 2 dashes Cayenne pepper 2 tablespoons Coconut aminos 2 tablespoons Fresh ginger 5 cloves Fresh garlic 1 teaspoon Hoisin sauce 1 medium onion 1.5 teaspoons Rice vinegar 2 pinches Seaweed 1 tablespoon Spicy bean paste 2 tablespoons Toasted sesame seed oil 8 cups Vegetable broth Mix-ins 1 bunch Baby bok choy 2 packs Tofu as desired Mushrooms as desired Other vegetables enough Ramen noodles Garnish Sesame seeds Lemon juice Steps Chop tofu as desired and fry two sides.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<h3 id="broth">Broth</h3>
<div class="ingredients">
<ul>
<li>2 dashes Cayenne pepper</li>
<li>2 tablespoons Coconut aminos</li>
<li>2 tablespoons Fresh ginger</li>
<li>5 cloves Fresh garlic</li>
<li>1 teaspoon Hoisin sauce</li>
<li>1 medium onion</li>
<li>1.5 teaspoons Rice vinegar</li>
<li>2 pinches Seaweed</li>
<li>1 tablespoon Spicy bean paste</li>
<li>2 tablespoons Toasted sesame seed oil</li>
<li>8 cups <a href="/posts/b3c5a8d6-11f0-4882-8bd1-dc4a09eca8c5/">Vegetable broth</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3 id="mix-ins">Mix-ins</h3>
<div class="ingredients">
<ul>
<li>1 bunch Baby bok choy</li>
<li>2 packs Tofu</li>
<li>as desired Mushrooms</li>
<li>as desired Other vegetables</li>
<li>enough Ramen noodles</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3 id="garnish">Garnish</h3>
<div class="ingredients">
<ul>
<li>Sesame seeds</li>
<li>Lemon juice</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h2 id="steps">Steps</h2>
<ol>
<li>Chop tofu as desired and fry two sides. (Use air fryer so there is no oil) or fry till crispy in oil in non stick frying pan</li>
<li>Dice onions, sauté in oil in large soup pot.  Add rice vinegar 3 minutes in. Add cayenne paper. Sauté for 3 more minutes. Add in garlic and ginger. Sauté for 3 minutes or till done. Add veggie broth. Bring to a simmer. Add in all sauces and bean paste. Stir well. Add in ramen noodles. Cook for 3 minutes. Add in bok choy (and any other veggies). Cook for at least 5 minutes. Add in seaweed. Cook for 5 more minutes.</li>
<li>Serve in bowls. Sprinkle sesame seeds and lemon juice on top.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="flashcards">Flashcards</h2>
<h2 id="backlinks">Backlinks</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="/posts/05911fff-a79b-4462-bf6d-a3cec4e1c9f2/#node-types">Node types</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>