<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>@cashweaver on Cash Weaver</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/tags/cashweaver/</link><description>Recent content in @cashweaver on Cash Weaver</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 20:32:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cashweaver.com/tags/cashweaver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>README</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 20:32:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/readme/</guid><description>The purpose of this README is to explain some of the details in this collection of content. In no particular order:
I haven&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;written&amp;rdquo; all of the posts. I employ liberal use of quoting as a way of archiving. I use tags prefixed with @ to identify original authors (eg: @cashweaver). When PostA links to PostB, then a backlink to PostA will appear at the bottom of PostB (example). I often omit the source of a quote if there is only once source used in the entire post.</description></item><item><title>How I Write My Blog</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/how_i_write_my_blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 20:21:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/how_i_write_my_blog/</guid><description> I write and publish using Emacs, specifically Doom Emacs (my config), and a combination of org-roam and ox-hugo. I host the blog on github and store the post content in a separate github repo.</description></item><item><title>Read Gmail in Emacs with mbsync and mu4e</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read_gmail_in_emacs_with_mbsync_and_mu4e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 20:01:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read_gmail_in_emacs_with_mbsync_and_mu4e/</guid><description>This is a guide to setting up access to email from a Gmail account (eg: @gmail.com) within doom emacs using mu, mbsync (isync), and mu4e (mu for emacs).
You may have to complete additional steps if you are not using doom emacs, Gmail, or if your set-up differs from mine in other ways.
Prerequisites Please be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve completed these steps before continuing:
Required Software Install mbsync version &amp;gt;= 1.</description></item><item><title>Read Gmail in Emacs with notmuch and lieer</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read_gmail_in_emacs_with_notmuch_and_lieer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 19:56:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/read_gmail_in_emacs_with_notmuch_and_lieer/</guid><description>This is a guide to setting up access to email (eg: @gmail.com) within doom emacs using notmuch and lieer.
You may have to complete additional steps if you are not using doom emacs or if your set-up differs from mine in other ways.
Prerequisites Please be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve completed these steps before continuing:
Required Software lieer
git clone https://github.com/gauteh/lieer.git cd lieer pip3 install -r requirements.txt notmuch</description></item><item><title>Create an OAuth2 Client ID</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/create_an_oauth2_client_id/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 19:48:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/create_an_oauth2_client_id/</guid><description>A short guide to creating an OAuth2 Client ID through the Google Cloud Console.
Create a new OAuth2 Client ID These steps are based on the steps outlined by ccrusius.
Navigate to the Cloud Console. Choose an existing project or create a new one. Select &amp;ldquo;APIs &amp;amp; Services&amp;rdquo; from the navigation menu. Select &amp;ldquo;Credentials&amp;rdquo;. Create new credentials of type &amp;ldquo;OAuth Client ID&amp;rdquo;. Choose application type &amp;ldquo;Other&amp;rdquo;. Choose a name for the client.</description></item><item><title>Idea Queue</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/idea_queue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 15:30:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/idea_queue/</guid><description> My blog post authoring process with emacs, org-mode, ox-hugo, and org-roam. Thoughts on productivity, guilt, and free time as an illusion. My process for managing my Anki cards in Emacs.</description></item><item><title>Polyphasic Sleep: 40 Day Trial Results</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/polyphasic_sleep_40_day_trial_results/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 12:15:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/polyphasic_sleep_40_day_trial_results/</guid><description>What would you do with another few hours every day? This was the thought that pulled me into attempting a polyphasic sleep schedule.
Note that I didn&amp;rsquo;t keep good notes while I was researching the intricacies of polyphasic sleep. There will be quite a few uncited claims.
Why Change My Sleep Schedule? In short: to live longer.
I expect to live for another 50.4 years1. I was getting an average of nine hours of sleep every night prior to stating this experiment.</description></item></channel></rss>