<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>cedric-chin on Cash Weaver</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/categories/cedric-chin/</link><description>Recent content in cedric-chin on Cash Weaver</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 08:57:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cashweaver.com/categories/cedric-chin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Expertise is Just Pattern Matching</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/expertise_is_just_pattern_matching/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 08:57:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/expertise_is_just_pattern_matching/</guid><description>Summary Expertise is just pattern matching. In other words, being an expert at something is equivalent to being really good at (1) recognizing situations and (2) knowing how to respond to those situations. Simple, right?
Notes [&amp;hellip;] the notion that &amp;lsquo;expertise is simply pattern-matching’ [&amp;hellip;] follows naturally from two other ideas that I’ve covered extensively on Commonplace over the past year.
The first idea is the ‘recognition-primed decision making’ model developed by psychologist Gary Klein and his collaborators, working in the US military and with expert firefighters and NICU nurses.</description></item><item><title>Three Kinds of Non-Fiction Books</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/three_kinds_of_non_fiction_books/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:22:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/three_kinds_of_non_fiction_books/</guid><description>Narrative Narrative books are books that tell a story. Examples include biographies, memoirs, and histories.
Tree Tree books are books that lay out a framework of ideas. A good example is Daniel Kahneman&amp;rsquo;s Thinking: Fast and Slow, which lays out his life&amp;rsquo;s work — the entirety of behavioural economics — in a single book. (So an entire field, like a tree of knowledge, in one book. Geddit, geddit?</description></item><item><title>Career Moat</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/career_moat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:21:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/career_moat/</guid><description> A career moat is an individual’s ability to maintain competitive advantages over your competition (say, in the job market) in order to protect your long term prospects, your employability, and your ability to generate sufficient financial returns to support the life you want to live. Just like a medieval castle, the moat serves to protect those inside the fortress and their riches from outsiders.</description></item></channel></rss>