<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>memory on Cash Weaver</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/categories/memory/</link><description>Recent content in memory on Cash Weaver</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:05:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cashweaver.com/categories/memory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Permastore</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/permastore/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:05:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/permastore/</guid><description>Extremely long-term or lasting memory which forms following extensive training, learning, or experience.
Bahrick posited the concept in https://books.google.com/books?vid=ISBN10.1037/0096-3445.113.1.1.</description></item><item><title>Testing Effect</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/testing_effect/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 11:36:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/testing_effect/</guid><description>Retrieving a piece of information from memory will increase ones ability to recall that piece of information over long periods of time. A common example would be using tests as a tool for study. The student has to attempt to recall the information from memory while taking the test and thereby improves their recall.</description></item><item><title>Memory in Educational Settings</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/memory_in_educational_settings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 10:31:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/memory_in_educational_settings/</guid><description>Summary Retrieval or re-experiencing a memory will increase retention. Studying should be somewhat difficult; neither too difficult that the subject is unable to overcome the challenge, nor too easy. The difficulty is a desirable feature of the process of studying in that the difficulty improves retention. One does not need to be aware of the specific benefits of a study method to benefit from them. The way you learned a piece of information as well as the cues/environment during retrieval control your ability to remember and utilize information.</description></item><item><title>Spacing Effect</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/spacing_effect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 15:26:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/spacing_effect/</guid><description> The spacing effect demonstrates that learning is more effective when study sessions are spaced out.</description></item></channel></rss>