<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>@anna-salamon on Cash Weaver</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/tags/anna-salamon/</link><description>Recent content in @anna-salamon on Cash Weaver</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:11:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cashweaver.com/tags/anna-salamon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Humans are not Automatically Strategic</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/humans_are_not_automatically_strategic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:11:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/humans_are_not_automatically_strategic/</guid><description>Why will a randomly chosen eight-year-old fail a calculus test? Because most possible answers are wrong, and there is no force to guide him to the correct answers. (There is no need to postulate a “fear of success”; most ways writing or not writing on a calculus test constitute failure, and so people, and rocks, fail calculus tests by default.)
Why do most of us, most of the time, choose to &amp;ldquo;pursue our goals&amp;rdquo; through routes that are far less effective than the routes we could find if we tried?</description></item><item><title>Learned Blankness</title><link>http://cashweaver.com/posts/learned_blankness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:07:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://cashweaver.com/posts/learned_blankness/</guid><description>Martin Seligman coined the term &amp;ldquo;learned helplessness&amp;rdquo; to describe a condition in which someone has learned to behave as though they were helpless. I think we need a term for learned helplessness about thinking (in a particular domain). I’ll call this “learned blankness”. Folks who fall prey to learned blankness may still take actions &amp;ndash; sometimes my students practiced the procedures again and again, hired a tutor, etc. But they do so as though carrying out rituals to an unknown god &amp;ndash; parts of them may be trying, but their “understand X” center has given up.</description></item></channel></rss>