<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>recipe on Cash Prokop-Weaver</title><link>http://cashpw.com/categories/recipe/</link><description>Recent content in recipe on Cash Prokop-Weaver</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 08:21:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cashpw.com/categories/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creamy vegan mushroom lasagna</title><link>http://cashpw.com/posts/0905eaa4-16e9-4abb-b78c-0b00f855e60d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 08:21:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashpw.com/posts/0905eaa4-16e9-4abb-b78c-0b00f855e60d/</guid><description>This recipe is from (Murnane 2017) and (Murnane n.d.).
Ingredients Olive, grape seed, or coconut oil, or veggie broth for sautéing 3 garlic cloves, minced 16 ounces mushrooms, chopped (you can use a mix of different mushrooms) 1 tablespoon tamari or coconut aminos 1 teaspoon dried thyme 3/4 cup raw cashews, soaked for a few hours (overnight is best), drained 1 cup veggie broth 2 big handfuls spinach 10 ounces gluten-free lasagna noodles 4 cups marinara sauce, store-bought or homemade Nutritional yeast (optional) Steps Preheat the oven to 350ºF.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This recipe is from (<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_1">Murnane 2017</a>) and (<a href="#citeproc_bib_item_2">Murnane n.d.</a>).</p>
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<div class="ingredients">
<ul>
<li>Olive, grape seed, or coconut oil, or veggie broth for sautéing</li>
<li>3 garlic cloves, minced</li>
<li>16 ounces mushrooms, chopped (you can use a mix of different mushrooms)</li>
<li>1 tablespoon tamari or coconut aminos</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dried thyme</li>
<li>3/4 cup raw cashews, <strong>soaked for a few hours (overnight is best)</strong>, drained</li>
<li>1 cup veggie broth</li>
<li>2 big handfuls spinach</li>
<li>10 ounces gluten-free lasagna noodles</li>
<li>4 cups marinara sauce, store-bought or homemade</li>
<li>Nutritional yeast (optional)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h2 id="steps">Steps</h2>
<ol>
<li>Preheat the oven to 350ºF.</li>
<li>In a large skillet, heat a glug of oil or veggie broth over medium. When the pan is hot, add the garlic and sauté until it becomes fragrant. This will take about a minute. Add the mushrooms, tamari, and thyme. Cook, stirring every minute or so, for 6 to 8 minutes or until the mushrooms release their water and a little broth starts to form.</li>
<li>Combine the cashews and veggie broth in a high-speed blender and blend until the mixture is completely smooth. This might take up to 5 minutes, depending on the speed and power of your blender. Pour the cashew sauce into the pan with the mushrooms. Reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer for a couple minutes to let the sauce thicken, stirring frequently. Throw in the spinach and stir for another minute.</li>
<li>Prepare the lasagna noodles according to the package instructions. Make sure to do this after your mushroom sauce is ready to go, so the noodles don&rsquo;t sit for too long and start sticking together.</li>
<li>Spread a third of the marinara sauce on the bottom of an 8-by-11-inch baking dish. Add a layer of noodles. Cover the noodles with half of the mushroom cream. Add a layer of noodles. Use another third of the marinara to cover these noodles. Add the remaining mushroom cream. Add the last layer of noodles and cover it with the remaining marinara sauce.</li>
<li>Cover the lasagna with aluminum foil and bake for 30 minutes. Remove the foil, add a sprinkle of nutritional yeast over the top, if you like, and bake for another 15 minutes. Let the lasagna rest for 5 minutes before serving.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<style>.csl-entry{text-indent: -1.5em; margin-left: 1.5em;}</style><div class="csl-bib-body">
  <div class="csl-entry"><a id="citeproc_bib_item_1"></a>Murnane, Jessica. 2017. <i>One Part Plant: A Simple Guide to Eating Real, One Meal at a Time</i>. First edition. New York, NY: Harper Wave, an imprint of HarperCollinsPublishers.</div>
  <div class="csl-entry"><a id="citeproc_bib_item_2"></a>———. n.d. “Creamy Vegan Mushroom Lasagna.” <i>Epicurious</i>. Accessed October 31, 2022. <a href="https://www.epicurious.com/recipes/food/views/creamy-mushroom-lasagna">https://www.epicurious.com/recipes/food/views/creamy-mushroom-lasagna</a>.</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Cayla's quarantine ramen</title><link>http://cashpw.com/posts/9b56dca0-39e0-4dec-a269-dd7773257c2b/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://cashpw.com/posts/9b56dca0-39e0-4dec-a269-dd7773257c2b/</guid><description>Ingredients Broth 2 dashes Cayenne pepper 2 tablespoons Coconut aminos 2 tablespoons Fresh ginger 5 cloves Fresh garlic 1 teaspoon Hoisin sauce 1 medium onion 1.5 teaspoons Rice vinegar 2 pinches Seaweed 1 tablespoon Spicy bean paste 2 tablespoons Toasted sesame seed oil 8 cups Vegetable broth Mix-ins 1 bunch Baby bok choy 2 packs Tofu as desired Mushrooms as desired Other vegetables enough Ramen noodles Garnish Sesame seeds Lemon juice Steps Chop tofu as desired and fry two sides.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<h3 id="broth">Broth</h3>
<div class="ingredients">
<ul>
<li>2 dashes Cayenne pepper</li>
<li>2 tablespoons Coconut aminos</li>
<li>2 tablespoons Fresh ginger</li>
<li>5 cloves Fresh garlic</li>
<li>1 teaspoon Hoisin sauce</li>
<li>1 medium onion</li>
<li>1.5 teaspoons Rice vinegar</li>
<li>2 pinches Seaweed</li>
<li>1 tablespoon Spicy bean paste</li>
<li>2 tablespoons Toasted sesame seed oil</li>
<li>8 cups <a href="/posts/b3c5a8d6-11f0-4882-8bd1-dc4a09eca8c5/">Vegetable broth</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3 id="mix-ins">Mix-ins</h3>
<div class="ingredients">
<ul>
<li>1 bunch Baby bok choy</li>
<li>2 packs Tofu</li>
<li>as desired Mushrooms</li>
<li>as desired Other vegetables</li>
<li>enough Ramen noodles</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3 id="garnish">Garnish</h3>
<div class="ingredients">
<ul>
<li>Sesame seeds</li>
<li>Lemon juice</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h2 id="steps">Steps</h2>
<ol>
<li>Chop tofu as desired and fry two sides. (Use air fryer so there is no oil) or fry till crispy in oil in non stick frying pan</li>
<li>Dice onions, sauté in oil in large soup pot.  Add rice vinegar 3 minutes in. Add cayenne paper. Sauté for 3 more minutes. Add in garlic and ginger. Sauté for 3 minutes or till done. Add veggie broth. Bring to a simmer. Add in all sauces and bean paste. Stir well. Add in ramen noodles. Cook for 3 minutes. Add in bok choy (and any other veggies). Cook for at least 5 minutes. Add in seaweed. Cook for 5 more minutes.</li>
<li>Serve in bowls. Sprinkle sesame seeds and lemon juice on top.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>